Did you know there are more people with genius IQ living in China
你知道中的天才人
than there are people of any kind living in the United States?
比美所有人都要多
That can't possibly be true.
@不可能
It is true.
是真的
What would account for that?
@怎麽可能呢
Well first of all, a lot of people live in China.
首先  中人口多
But here's my question:
但我的}是
How do you distinguish yourself
你如何能自己在一群SAT[美高考]
in a population of people who all got 1600 on their SAT's?
考中都拿1600分的人中突@出砟
I didn't know they take SAT in China.
在中他不用⒓SAT考
They dont,I wasn't talking about China anymore, I was talking about me.
他不用  我f的不是中  我f我自己
You got 1600?
你考了一千六百分
Yes. I can sing in a Acapella group. But I cant sing.
]e  我在合唱F可以清唱但我自己不唱
Does that mean that you actually got nothing wrong?
那不是f你考一}都]e
Or you row crew or you invent a 25 dollar PC.
是f可以⒓淤艇或l明二十五美元X了
Or you get into a final club.
或者加入KO俱凡
Or you get into a final club, exactly.
]e  也可以加入KO俱凡
You know from a woman's perspective
你知道囊女人的角度看
sometimes not being in an Accapella group can be a good thing.
不⒓用缆合唱Ff不定是件好事
This is serious.
我是J真的
Well I am admitting I do like guys who row crew.
我承J我喜g艇的男生
Well I cant do that.
可惜我不划船
I was kidding.
我_玩笑的
Yes. I got nothing wrong on the test.
是的  我考一}]e
Have you ever tried?
你^划船
I'm trying now.
正L著
To row crew?
加入艇
To get into a final club. To row crew?
加入KO俱凡  你f⒓淤艇啊
No. Are you, like-whatever-delusional?
我不  你是不是有c妄想症啊
Maybe just sometimes.
可能有r候吧
Sometimes, you say two things at once
有r候你同r杉事情
and I'm not sure which one we're aiming at.
我都不知道你什麽r候就切Q}了
But you've seen guys who row crew, right?
你^艇的那些人  是吧
No.
]^
Okay, well, they are bigger than me.
好吧  他比我高大
They're the world class athletes.
他都是世界的\T
And a second ago you said you like guys who row crew
你才f你喜g艇的男生碇
so I assumed you'd met one.
所以我J你是^他的
I guess I meant I liked the idea of it.
我想我f的是加入艇那主意不e
The way a girl likes cowboys.
就像女孩子都喜g牛仔一
Okay.
好吧
Should we get something to eat?
我要不要c|西沓园
Would you rather talk about something else?
你是不是更想ce的事情呢
No, it's just that since the beginning of the
]有  只是挠@些KO俱凡块_始
conversation about finals clubs I think I may have missed a birthday.
我X得都快^完一生日了
There are more people in China with genius iQ than the entire population of...?
中天才的人嫡娴亩噙^美人口
The Phoenix is the most diverse.
P凰俱凡渴亲钛}s的
The Fly Club, Roosevelt punched the Porc.
有w翔俱凡  _斯福加入了烤瓷俱凡
Which one?
哪_斯福
The Porcelain, the Porc, it's the best of the best.
烤瓷俱凡  Q烤瓷  是最尖的
Which Roosevelt.
我其的是哪_斯福
Theodore.
Theodore
Is it true they send a bus around
是不是真的他得派公共汽
to pick up girls who want to party with the next chairman?
去接要和下任主席一起⒓优Φ呐孩
You can see why it's so important to get in.
你可以看得出加入@俱凡康闹匾性了吧
Okay, well, which is the easiest one to get into?
好吧  哪是最容易加入的
Why would you ask me that?
你什麽我@
I was just asking.
就S便
None of them. That's the point.
]有容易M的  @才是PI
Our freind Eduardo made $300,000
我朋友Eduardo去年夏天靠
betting on oil future last summer and
石油前景炅巳十f美元
Eduardo won't come close to getting in.
就@Eduardo想M差得h呢
The ability to make money doesn't impress anybody around here.
@Y的人根本不把赍X能力放在眼Y
Must be nice.
一定很害
He made $300,000 in a summer?
他一夏天炅巳十f美元啊
He likes Meteorology.
他喜g庀W
I thought it was oil futures.
我以他的是石油前景
You can read the weather,
你能x懂天
you can predict the price of heating oil.
你就能Ay民用燃料油的rX
I think you asked me that because you think the final
你那麽我是不是X得只有
club that's easiest to get into is the one where I'll have the best chance.
最容易M的KO俱凡课也抛钣邢Ｍ啊
I...what?
我...什麽
You asked me which one was the easiest to
你我哪是最容易M的俱凡
get into because you think that's where I have the best chance.
因你X得在那Y我才最有C
The one that's easiest to get into would be the one where anybody had the best chance.
T最低的俱凡空l都容易M
You didnt ask which one was the best one,
你的不是哪是最好的
you asked me which one was the easiest.
你我哪是最容易M的
I was honestly just asking. Okay? I was asking just to ask.
我就只是  行  我就
Mark, I'm not speaking in code.
我]有影射其他  Mark
Erica
Erica
You're obsessed with the finals clubs.
你已KO俱凡窟^于O端了
You have finals clubs OCD and you need to see someone about this
你得了KO俱凡壳科戎  你需要看看t生
who'll prescribe some sort of medication.
他_c核碇沃
You don't care if side effects may include blindness,
你不在乎副作用是不是你瞎眼
Final clubs,
是'final clubs'
not finals clubs.
不是'finals clubs'
And there's a difference between being obsessed and being motivated.
而且O端和eO是不一
Yes. There is.
]e  是不一
Well, what you do, that was cryptic, so you do speak in code.
你瞧  你就是含糊其o  就是有所指
I didn't mean to be cryptic.
我]有含糊其o
All I'm saying I need to do something
我所要f的就是我需要做些有意x的事
substantial in order to get the attention of the clubs.
碜那些俱凡孔⒁獾轿
Why?
什麽
Because they are exclusive.
因他特
And fun and they lead me to a better life.
有啡漳茏我^的更好
You think Teddy Roosevelt got elected
你JTeddy Rooseveltx
president because he was a member of the Phoenix Club?
y就是因他曾是P凰俱凡恳T
He was a member of the Porcellian and yes he did.
他是烤瓷俱凡康  涨椅揖褪沁@诱J的
Well why dont you concentrate on being the best you, you can be.
你何不集中精力做你所能做的最好的自己
Did you really just say that
你是J真那诱f的
I was kidding
_玩笑的
I'm just stating the fact and that doesn't make it any less true.
我只是述事涨椅艺f的一c阂膊贿^分啊
I want to be straight forward and tell you that
我就直f吧
I think you should be a lot more supportive.
我X得你多支持我
If I get in i'll be taking you to the events and the gatherings
如果我入了我可以你去⒓痈鞣N集
and you'll be meeting people that you wouldn't normally get to meet .
你有幸到平常你很y到的大人物
You would do that for me?
你真我去
Indeed.
真的
Okay I want to try and be straight forward with you
好  我就跟你直f了  我告V你
and let you know that were not anymore.
我不再是一毫
What do you mean?
你什麽意思
We were not dating anymore, I'm sorry.
我不再s了  Σ黄
Is this a joke?
@是玩笑
No, it's not.
不  是真的
You're breaking up with me?
你要跟我分手
You're going to introduce me to people I wouldn't normally get to meet?
你要介B我JR一些我平常不到的大人物
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
@f的是什麽混~啊
Settle down.
冷o下
What was it supposed to mean?
你那是什麽意思啊
Erica, the reason we're able to sit here and drink is
Erica  我之所以能坐在@Y是
that you used to sleep with the door guy.
因你^去和看T那砘锷线^床
The door guy, his name is Bobby.
看T那人有名字  叫Bobby
I haven't slept with the door guy, the door guy's a friend of mine.
我]跟他上^床  他是我的一朋友
He's a perfectly good class of people
他是秀的一等公民
and what part of Long-Island are you from?
你又是拈Lu哪里冒出淼陌
Wimbledon?
Wimbledon
Wait.
等等
I'm going back to my dorm.
我要回宿舍了
Is this real?
@是真的
Yes.
是的
Then wait, I apologize, okay?
那等等  我道歉  好不好
I have to go...
我必走了...
Erica
Erica
Yes?
怎麽啦
I'm sorry and I mean it..
Σ黄  我真心的
I appreciate that but I have to study
我很感激但我要去W了
Come on. You don't have to study.
e@  你不是要回去W的
You don't have to study. Let's just talk.
你不必回去的  我好
I can't.
我不能
Why?
什麽不
Because it's exhausting.
因我精疲力竭了
Dating you is like dating a stairmaster.
跟你s就像根跑步Cs
All I meant is that you're not likely to...currently
我所f的就是你不必要F在...
I wasn't making an coment on your parents.
我不是在u嗄愀改
I was saying you go to B.U.
我只是f你要去波士D大W
I was stating a fact. That's all.
我就是述事  就@
If you think I'm rude...
如果你J我太粗
I have to go study.
我要去看了
You don't have to study.
你不必去的
Why do you keep saying I dont have to study?
你什麽f我不用W啊
Because you go to B.U.!
因你就念波士D大W啊
Do you want to get some food?
想吃c什麽
I'm sorry you're not sufficiently impressed with my education.
非常抱歉我的大W]能你M意
And I'm sorry I don't have a rowboat.
我也抱歉我]有艇
So were even.
所以我扯平了
I think we should just be friends.
我X得我只做朋友就好
I don't want friends.
我不需要朋友
I was being polite, I had no intention of being friends with you.
我那是客  我一c阂膊幌敫你做朋友
I'm under some pressure right now from my O.S. class.
我F在因操作系ynI倍感毫
If we could just order some food, I think we should...
我要c|西吃  我想我能...
Listen, you're probably going to be a very succesful computer person.
著  你也S能在IT界大有作
But you're going to go through life thinking that girls don't
但生活中你却一直苦琅孩子不喜g你
like you because you're a nerd.
是因你是呆子
And I want you to know, from the bottom of my heart, that won't be true.
我想告V你的是  我打心底不@诱J
It'll be because you're an asshole.
那是因你是混蛋
Erica Albright is a bitch.
Erica Albright是婊子
Do you think that's because her family changed
你X得是因她家人Albrecht改姓
their name from Albrecht or do you think it's because all B.U. Girls are bitches?
是你X得所有波士D大W的女生都是婊子呢
For the record, she may look like a 34C
特此明  她也S看著有三十四C
but she's getting all kinds of help from our friends at Victoria's Secret.
但那全是S胸纫碌淖饔
She's a 34B, as in barely anything there.
她只有三十四B  Y面缀蹩湛杖缫
False advertising.
全是
The truth is she has a nice face.
情是她蛋哼不e
I need to do something to take my mind off her.
我需要做c什麽才能D移我的注意力
Easy enough, except I need an idea.
f著  可就是我]好主意
I'm a little intoxicated, I'm not gonna lie.
我有c喝醉了  我是不撒e的
So what if it's not even 10PM and it's a Tuesday night?
@m不是周末之夜又有什麽PS呢
The Kirkland facehook is open on my desktop
我@公寓的Facebook_在我桌面上
and some of these people have pretty horrendous facebook pics.
有的人放著可怕的Facebook照片
Billy Olson's sitting here and had the idea of putting some of
比利?W森坐在@Y  他出了主意
the pictures next to pictures of farm animals
f把@些照片和家禽放在一起
and have people vote on who's hotter.
然後大家投票看l更火辣
Good call, Mr.Olson
@主意不e啊  Olson先生
Yeah, it's on.
我_始吧
I'm not gonna do the farm animals
我不浞偶仪菡
but I like the idea of comparing two people together.
但我X得比^人@主意不e
It gives the whole thing a very
它整件事有N"D`C"的感X
"Turing"
[一N可不受Υ嫒萘肯拗频募傧胗算C]
feel since people's ratings of the pictures will be more implicit than, say, choosing a number to represent each person's hotness like they do on hotornot.com.
因@比用底执表崂背潭鹊木W站更含蓄
The first thing we're going to need is a lot of pictures.
首先我需要S多照片
Unfortunately, Harvard doesn't keep a public centralized facebook
不幸的是哈佛]有公共公_的Facebook
so I'm going to get all the images from the individual houses that people are in.
所以我母髯运奚岬碾XI取他照片
Let the hacking begin.
黑客要出隽
First up is Kirkland.
首先Kirkland_始
They keep everything open
@Y的一切都是公_的
and allow indexes in their Apache configuration,
赵试S在ApacheY插入索引
so a little WGET magic
所以用WGET就足以下d整
is all that's necessary to download the entire Kirkland facebook.
Kirkland的FacebookD片了
Kids stuff.
小孩游
Next is Elliot.
接下硎Elliot公寓
They're also open but with no indexes on Apache.
他也是公_的但在Apache上]有索引
I can run an empty search
我能M行一空白搜索
and it returns all of the images in the database in a single page.
接著煅Y的所有D片就呈雾@示出
Then I can save the page and Mozilla
然後我保存W  摩斯拉[g[器名]
will save all the images for me.
臀冶４嬲掌
Excellent.
好O了
Moving right along.
M展不e
Excuse me, everybody.
大家注意一下
You are in one of the oldest,
你F在所在的是全世界不只是哈佛
one of the most exclusive clubs, not just in Havard, in the world.
最古老最有特色俱凡恐一
Now I would welcome you to Phoenix first party of the falls emester
F在我宣布P凰俱凡壳W期第一次舞_始
Lowell has some security.
Lowell怯邪踩防o
They require a username/password combo,
需要要用裘和密aM合
and I'm going to go ahead and say they don't have access to main FAS user database,
我直接M入章Q他]有FAS用嘞
so they have no way of detecting an intrusion
所以他]k法察X到@次侵入
Adams has no security
Adams]有安全W
but limits the number of results to 20 a page.
但每O限只@示二十Y果
All I have to is break up the same script I used on Lowell and it's set.
我只需用在_威使用^的相同程式即可破解
Quincy has no online Facebook,
Quincy]有在QFacebook
what a sham.
太可惜了
Nothing I can do about that.
Υ宋乙o能力
Dunster is intense.
Dunster呛茈y搞
Not only is there no public directory but there's no directory at all.
那Y不H]有公共目  是任何目都]有
You have to do searches and
你必M行搜索
every search returns more than 20 matches nothing is returned.
每搜索超^二十Y果t什麽都不@示
Once you do get results they don't link directly to the images,
一旦有Y果  它不直接B接到D片
they link to a PHP that redirects or something. Weird.
而是B接到人W或e的什麽  很奇怪
This maybe diffucult, I'll come back later.
@估比^y搞定  我回^再弄
- Hey, Sheldon's up. - What?
-Sheldon醒了 -你f什麽
- Great wine, beautiful fish. - Thanks.
-害的酒  漂亮的~  -xx分享
Leverett is a little better.
Leverett巧晕⒑命c
It's still make you search but you
然你得M行搜索  但是
can do an empty search and gets links to pages with every student's picture.
空白搜索接到有每W生照片的W上
It's slightly obnoxious that they let you view one picture at a time.
但每次只能g[一@有c
And there's no way I am gonna go to 500 hundred pages,
我是不可能去g[五百W
to download pictures one hundred times.
硐螺d一百次照片的
So its definitely necessary to break out the EMACS
因此退出EMACS
and modify that Perl script.
硇薷Perl代a就非常必要了
Done.
搞定了
What's going on?
怎麽啦
Perfect timing. Eduardo's here
rg正好  Eduardo砹
and he's going to have the key ingredient.
他有我最需要的|西
- Mark -What up?
-Mark  -怎麽啦
You and Erica split up?
你和Erica分手啦
How did you know that?
你怎麽知道的
It's on your blog.
你博客上都著呢
Oh yeah.
哦  是啊
Are you alright?
你好吧
I need you.
我需要你兔
I'm here for you.
我就是你而
No, I need the algorithm you used for the oil futures.
不是@  我需要你石油A期r的公式
Are you okay?
你]事喊
We're ranking girls.
我在o女孩子排名
You mean other students.
你f其他女W生
Yeah.
是的
You think that's such a good idea?
你X得@是好主意
I need the algorithm.
我需要那\算公式
Give each girl a base rating of 1400.
o每女孩一千四百的基A分
At any time "Girl A" has a rating R-a
在某一r刻女孩A得到R-a的u分
and "Girl B" has e rating R-b.
女孩B得到R-b的u分
When any two girls are matched up there's
θ我女孩M行u比r
an expectation of which will win based on their current rating.
有根F有u分M行的Ay
Yeah.
]e
And Those expectations are expressed this way.
@些Ay出砭褪沁@拥
Let's write it.
我程序吧
The one on the left.
左那
On the right.
右的
The right.
右
It works.
@可以用了
Who should we send it to first?
我先鹘ol呢
- Dwyer. - Neal.
- Dwyer  - Neal
Who are you gonna send it to?
你打算先鹘ol呢
Just a Couple of people. The question is, who are they gonna send it to?
就那麽人  }是  他鹘ol呢
Hey guys, check this out.
大夥哼^砜纯
The one on the left.
左那
These girls, right or Left?
@些女孩  x右是左
Left.
左
Right or Left?
右是左
That's my roommate.
那是我室友
Oh my God. On the left.
天哪  左的
This is pathetic.
真可悲
Right.
右
Left.
左
Shit!
鬼
Albright, he blogged about you.
Albright他在博客中f你了
You don't want to read this.
你不想看到的
Erica, is this yours?
Erica  @是你的胸衣
I stole it from a trainee.
我男律那Y偷淼
Get the hell out of here.
o我L出去
Thats an awful lot of traffic.
@流量真TM的大啊
You think maybe we should shut it down before we get into trouble.
你f我是不是在它惹麻┣鞍阉P了啊
Hello?
喂
Wait wait wait...
慢著  慢cf...
At 4 in the morning?
在R晨四c
Well there is an unusual amount of traffic which occured.
那Y有流量异常W站
Your saying its unusal for 4 in the morning?
你f不正常是fR晨四c不有那流量
No, this would be unusuall
不  就算是在超碗比中
for half time at the superbowl.
@流量也不正常
Alright.
好吧
I gotta go in.
我得去工作
What's going on?
出什麽事了
The Harvard network is about to crash.
哈佛的Wj要崩⒘
You dont think...
你f不是...
I do.
是的
God saves us everybody.
上帝保佑我每人吧
Can't connect.
B接不上
The network is down.
Wjc了
Unless this is a coincidence I would think this is us.
如果不是巧合  我X得是我造成的
It's not a coincidence.
@不是巧合
Oh shit.
哦  鬼
So you're called in front of the ad. board.
所以f你被校委玖
That's not what happened.
不是那拥
You weren't called in front of the administartive board.
你]被校委
No, back, let's back at the bar
不  先倒回去  回到和
with Erica Albright.
Erica Albright在酒吧那晚
She said all that? That I said that stuff to her.
她那麽f  我跟她f了那拥脑
I was reading from the transcript of her deposition.
我是看著她的C~f的
Why wold you even need to depose her?
你究竟什麽要她作C啊
That's really for us to decide.
@是我考]的事
You think if I know she could make me look like a jerk,
你X得如果她把我f的像混蛋
I'll be more likely to settle.
我就同意和解的
Mark don't.
Mark  ef了
Why dont we stretch our legs for a minute, can we do that?
我休息一分吧  可以
It's been almost 3 hours and frankly you did spend an awful lot of time
都三小r了  老f你浪M了那麽多rg
embarassing Mr.Zuckerburg
就想用一女孩在酒吧的C~
with the girls testimony from the bar.
Zuckerburg先生y堪
I am not embarassed, she just made a lot of that up.
我]X得y堪  只是她的都是胡y造的
She was under Oath.
她l^誓的
I guess that would be the first time someone lied under Oath.
我想她y道是第一起誓後做假C的
They got 2200 hits within 2 hours.
他小r赛c袈示陀汕砂俣
- Thousands. - What?
-f  -什麽
22 thousand.
扇f汕Т
Those guys are really fast.
@砘得真快
Is there anyway to make this a fair fight?
有什麽k法能比看起聿灰郧R弱
Jump out and swim.
跳M水Y游泳^去
We'd have to jump out and drown.
我得跳M水Y淹死他才能A
Or you can row forward and I can row backward.
要不你向前我向後
We are genectically identical, science says we would stay in one place.
我是同卵p胞胎  科W上碚f我是同一的
Just row the damn boat.
就Ｐ你的船吧
You hear about this?
你f了
What?
什麽
Two nights ago, a sophomore
商烨暗耐砩  一名Kirkland的大二W生
choked the network with a laptop from Kirkland.
用他的P本弄c了Wj
- Reanlly? - At four a.m..
-真的  -R晨四c...
He set up a website we vote the hotness of female undergrads.
他建了uxW校最辣女生的W站
What were we doing, that none of us heard about this.
r我在质谗  ]f啊
I do not know, three-hour low-technical row before breakfast,
不清楚  三小r的餐前皮艇
full course load studying.
然後一股X忙W
Another three hours in the tank then studying.
在泳池泡了三小r ^mW
I'm not sure how we missed it.
不知道怎麽e^了
How much activity was on this thing?
@玩意受g迎
Twenty-two thousand page requests.
扇f汕Т雾面求
Twenty-two thousand?
扇f汕
This guy hacked Facebook, seven houses.
@砘锖诹似堑Facebook
He developed the site in one night
他用一晚上就建起了W站
and he did it while he was drunk.
r醉得不p
Twenty-two thousand.
扇f汕
How do you know he was drunk?
你怎麽知道他醉了
He was blogging, while doing this.
他做W站敲博客
Know what I think?
知道我怎麽想
Way ahead of you.
f
This is our guy.
咱就找他了
Cameron Winklevoss,
Cameron Winklevoss
W-I-N-K-L-E-V-O-S-S
W-I-N-K-L-E-V-O-S-S
Cameron spelt the usuall way.
常的Cameron
Taylor Winklevoss, Taylor spelt the usuall way.
Taylor Winklevoss  常的Taylor
My last name's the same as my brother's.
跟我哥一姓
Mr. Zuckerberg, this is an administrative board hearing.
Zuckerberg先生  @是行政委T的C
violating copyright, violating individual privacy
你涉嫌破陌踩系y  侵犯版嘁约扒址人[私
by creating the website www.facemash.com.
F受到起V
You also charged with being in violation of universty policy
你被控`反了
on distribution of digitised images.
W校鞑荡a照片的定
Before we begin with our questioning,
在我提之前
your allowed to make a statement, would you like to do so?
你可以作出相的明  你要@幼
I've...you know
我已...著
I have already apologised in the Crimson, to the AVHW
我已在校笊AVHW
to Harvard's Latina
Harvard's Latina
and to any women at Harvard who might have been insulted, as I take it that they were'
哈佛任艺J可能受到侮辱的女生  M行了道歉
As for any charges stemming from the breach of security
至于那些P于破陌踩系y的控V
I believe I deserve some recognition from this board.
我X得委To予我一些肯定
- I'm sorry?  - Yes.
-你f什麽  -怎麽
I don't understand.
我不明白
Which part?
哪部分
You deserve recognition.
o予你一些肯定
I believe I pointed out some pretty gaping holes in your system.
我揭示了你系y中S多乐氐穆┒
- Excuse me, may I? - Yes.
-能打嘁幌  -v
Mr. Zuckerberg, I'm in charge of security
Zuckerberg先生  我
for all computers on the Harvard network.
哈佛所有X的Wj安全
I can assure you of its sophistication
我可以向你保CWj的性能
in fact it was that level of sophistication,
正因它异的性能
that led us to you in less then four hours.
我在四小r染筒榈搅四
Four hours?
四小r
Yes sir.
]e
That would be impressive except if you'd known
如果你]lF我在室窗羯系某绦
what you are looking for you would seen it written on my dorm room window.
那成算挺不e的
So six months academic probation.
留校察看六月
Wow,they had to make an example out of you.
他得⒁毁影
They had my blog.
他查了我的博客
I should have written nothing about the farm animals,
真不家畜那些|西的
that was stupid.
我真是太蠢了
I was kidding for gods sake doesn't anybody have a sense of humor?
我他不就_玩笑  一c幽默感都]有
I tried to stop you.
叫你不要弄的
I know.
知道
How do you do this thing
你做得@玩意是怎麽
when you manage to get all girls to hate us?
把我成所有女孩的\矢之的的
Why do I love China? I can't do that.
我怎麽喜g上中  不能啊
Suppose we were given a computer
假O我x予一台X
with a 16 bit virtual address, and a page size of 256 bytes.
16比特的M地址和256字的面大小
The system uses a one level page table
系y使用渭的分表
that starts at address 0x0400.
列表起始地址是0x400
Maybe you want DMA on your 16-bit system, who knows.
可能你想要你的16位系y有直接却嬖L功能  S意
The first few pages are reserved for the hardware flag etc..
前面文件被保留o硬件俗R等信息
assume page-table entries have eight status bits.
假O分表^有八B位
The eight status bits will then be...
@八B位⒆成...
I see we have our first surrender.
看碛械谝J的人了
Don't worry, Mr. Zuckerberg,
e心  Zuckerberg先生
brighter men then you have tried and failed this class.
比你明的人在@堂n上也吃了苦^
One valid bit, one modified bit,
一有效位  一修改位
one reference bit, five permission bit.
一⒖嘉  五允S位
That is correct.
答α
Does everybody see how he got there.
有人知道他是怎麽算的
Mark?
Mark
You Mark Zuckerberg?
你是Mark Zuckerberg
Yes.
是
I'm Cameron Winklevoss.
我是Cameron Winklevoss
Taylor Winklevoss.
Taylor Winklevoss
You guys related?
你是兄弟
Good, funny never heard that before.
得好  第一次有人@麽
What can I do for you?
找我有什麽事
Did I insult your girlfriends?
我招惹你女朋友了
Actually, I don't know.
f  我真不知道
We never asked.
我]^
We should.
的
Now,
好了
we have an idea we want to talk to you about.
我想跟你事
You got a minute?
有rg
You guys look like you spent some time at the gym.
你看起砗孟窠常去健身房
We have to.
]k法
Why?
什麽
We row crew.
艇的
Yeah, I've gotta minute.
我有rg了
Great.
太棒了
Have you ever been inside the PORCILE?
你是PORCILE的一T
No.
不是
We can not take you passed cause your not a member.
不是的就]法你M去了
That hurt.
悲
Sandwich or something?
睃c三明治什麽的
Uh... OK.
好的
Mark, right?
Mark是吧
Mark, this is Deweiya Narendra, our partner.
Mark  @是Deweiya Narendr  我的搭n
We were really impressed with "Facemash".
你的Facemash令我印象深刻
We checked you out. You also built "CourseMatch".
我查了下你的Y料  你建了CourseMatch
What is "CourseMatch"?
CourseMatch是什麽
You go online and see what courses your freinds are taking.
你可以上W查朋友都修了哪些n
Really smartness.
酷懒
Mark?
Mark
Yeah?
怎麽
We were talking about "CourseMatch".
我才正f著CourseMatch呢
Kind of a no-brainer.
小嚎频耐嬉
You invented something in high school, right?
你高中就弄^一些|西  是
An apply for MP3 player, that recognises your taste in music.
一MP3的用  能be每人歌的口味
Anybody try to buy it?
有I家
Microsoft.
微
How much?
多少X
For free?
免M
Why?
什麽
OK. Well, we have something we have been working on for a while.
好吧  我一直在v弄一活
We think it's great. It is called the "Harvard Connection"
我X得很不e  我叫它哈佛Wj
You can create your own page, interests, bios, freinds, pics...
你可以立自己的主  酆  介  朋友  照片
Then people can go online and see your bio.
人便能上W查看你的介
requests...
l送求...
Yeah how is that different from "My Space" and "Freindster"?
@跟My Space  Freindster有什麽^e
harvard.edu
harvard.edu
harvard.edu is the most prestigious e-mail address in the country.
harvard.edu是全最具望的]箱
And all concepts based on the idea that girls...
@些概念都建立在女孩...
Not a pretty thing, thus...
不是什麽正玩意  就是
Girls want to only go out with guys who go to Harvard.
女孩都想跟哈佛男s
Me and my brother don't have trouble putting thing.
我和我哥就不用心
Main different district while we were talking about is Myspcae,
它和我才的Myspace  Friendster
Friendster any of those other social networking sites.
以及其它@些社交Wj最主要的^e在于
It's exclusivity.
它一o二
Yeah we'd love for you to work with us, Mark.
十分希望你能c我合作  Mark
We need a programmer who is creative.
我需要一名有造性的程序T
And we know who can take the initiative.
我清楚它由lI^
Women's groups are ready to declare a fatwa, but you know...
"腐女"M封⒛愕  可你要知道...(英文y的。。YY)
This could help rehabilitate your image.
@能湍慊托蜗
Wow, you would do that for me.
你ξ疫真好啊
We'd like to work with you.
我希望c你合作
Our first programmer graduated and went to work for Google.
我的第一程序TI後去了Google
Our second programer is got overwhelmed with school work.
第二弄WI忙得焦^~
We would need you to build the site,
我需要你建立W站
write the code, we will provide...
代a  我提供...
I'm in.
算我一
What?
什麽
Awsome.
太棒了
That's what you said?
你是@麽f的
It was three or four years ago, I don't know what I said.
都三四年了  我不得我f^什麽
When did you come to Eduardo?
你什麽r候去找的Eduardo
I don't understand that question.
我不太明白@}
You remeber answering in the affirmative?
你得你o了肯定的回答
The affirmative.
肯定的
When did you come to Eduardo with the idea for Facebook.
你是何r了Facebook去找Eduardo的
It was called "The Facebook" then.
那r叫The Facebook
This doesn't need to be that diffucult.
@}不y啊
I'm currently in the middle of two different lawsuits.
我要同r付善鹪VA
Did you answer affirmatively?
Taylor和Cameron Winklevoss
When Taylor and Cameron Winklevoss
在十一月你建立哈佛Wjr
did in November ask you to build, "Harvard Connection,"
你作出^肯定的答
Did you say yes?
你同意了
I said I'd help.
我f我兔
When did you approach Mr. Savarin with the idea for the Facebook?
你何r去找Savarin先生探Facebook事宜的呢
I wouldn't say I approached him.
我可]f我找他
Sy?
Sy
You can answer the question.
你可以回答@}
At a party at Alpha Epsilon PI.
在一叫Alpha Epsilon PI的派ι
What's that?
什麽派
Jewish Fraternity.
q太x
It was Caribbean night.
加勒比海I之夜
It's not the guys like me generally attracted to Asian girls
什麽洲妞不uu我@N人而A倒
but Asian girls are generally attracted to guys like me?
是我@N人逐u拜倒在洲妞裙下
I don't know if an algorithm could find the connection of you and these Asian girls.
不知道有]有算法能你和洲妞配
I don't think it's that complicated, they're hot,
@算法不}s  她身材火辣
they're smart, they are not Jewish, they can't dance.
^X明  不是q太人  又不跳舞
Hey Mark is here!
Mark砹
Mark!
Mark
I think I've come up with something...
我想到c子...
Hang on, I have to tell you something you're not going to believe.
等等  我先告V你件不可思h的事
Come on.
f吧
I got punched by the Phoenix.
我收到P凰俱凡康难了
- Are you kidding? - No.
-你_玩笑吧  -不
It's just the first step before the process.
只是正式加入前的第一步
They send the invitation on Monday,
他周一l的邀函
by door tonight.
今晚我在T底下lF的
That's my first punched party tommorow.
明天我就要第一次⒓邮苎派α
- You got punched by the Phoenix. - Yeah.
-P凰俱凡垦你了  -
What did you want to talk to me about.
你要跟我f什麽碇
- Mark? - Yeah.
-Mark  -怎麽
You said you come up with something.
你f你想到c子
Yeah I think I've came up with something. Come outside.
]e   我想到主意  出去f
It's 20 degrees outside.
外面才二十度
I can't stair at that thing Niagra Falls,
我受不了那尼加拉大瀑布
it has absolutely nothing to do with the Carribean.
它跟加勒比海I八竿子打不著
- People came to "Facemash" to step in, right? - Yeah.
-人LFacemash  -
It wasn't because they saw pictures of hot girls,
詹皇悄切┟琅的照片吸引了他
you can go anywhere on the internet
因在W上
- and see pictures of hot girls.  - Yeah.
-美女的照片o不在  -
Because they saw pictures of girls that they knew.
而是因他能看到熟悉女生的照片
People want to go on the internet and check out their friends
大家想上WL他的朋友
so why not build a web site that offers them freinds, pictures, profiles
何不建一@拥木W站  提供朋友  照片  n案等信息
whatever you can visit browse around,
你可以S意g[
maybe someone you just met at a party.
甚至能L你在派JR的女孩
I'm not talking about a dating site.
我f的不是什麽交友W站
I'm talking about taking the entire social experience of college,
我指的是  ⒄大W的社交Wj
and putting it online.
搬到W上去
Can't feel my legs.
我的腿鼋┝
I know.
知道
- I'm totally psyched about this, Eduardo. - Yeah.
-@太令人d^了  Eduardo  -好啊
"It would be exclusive."
它一o二
You would have to know the people on the site
你必t解W上那人
to get past your own page, like...
才能同意他L你的面  就像...
getting punched.
收到邀
That's good.
有意思
It's like "Final Club", except we're the president.
@就像Final Club  只不^在@我f了算
I told him I thought it sounded great,
我f  @主意起聿诲e
It was a great idea.
是好主意
There was nothing to hack,
用不著去`取
people were gonna provide their own pictures, their own information.
人上髯约旱恼掌  填自己的Y料
And people would have the ability
可以x
to invite or not invite their friends to join.
是否邀自己的好友加入@Wj
In a world where social structure was everything?
想像一完全由社群M建的世界
That was the thing.
它就是那右世界
It was a big project,
@是浩大的工程
and he was going to have to write tens of thousands lines of code.
他要成千上f行代a
So I was wondering why he was coming to me and not his roommates.
我那r就想  什麽是他  而不是他室友碚椅
Dustin Moscovitz, Chris Hughes, they were programmers.
Dustin Moscovitz  Chris Hughes  他都是程序T
We're gonna need a little start up cash
需要一c淤Y金
to rent a server to get it online.
租一服掌骱米它上Q
So that was why.
那就是原因
- Did he offer terms. - Yes.
-他提l件了  -然
We'll split it 70/30.
咱三七分成
70 for me 30 for you for putting up the
你提供一千美元Y金
1000 dollars and for handling everything on the business end.
商者\作  你三我七吧
You're CFO.
你就是首席展
And you said...
你回答...
I said, "Let's do it".
我回答  就@麽至
OK, did he add anything else?
那麽  他f什麽了
Yes.
f了
It probably wasn't a diversity thing.
它也S]那麽}s
So what.
那又怎
Why you think he said that?
你X得他什麽要f那句
Gretchen, excuse me for interupting, whose discovery is this.
Gretchen  抱歉打嘁幌  我到底在l
Sy, if you let me continue with my line of questioning.
Sy  我先完
They are suggesting that I was jealous of Eduardo for getting punched
他想f  Eduardo收到P凰俱凡康难令我妒火中
by the Phoenix and began a plan to screw him out of a company that I hadn't even invent yet.
于是我⑺奈砉司的F中踢出去
Were you?
是
Gretchen!
Gretchen
Jealous of Eduardo?
嫉妒Eduardo
Stop typing we're all...
e了...
I know you've done your homework
我想你一定做足了功n
and know money is not a big part of my life.
知道我詹辉诤蹂X
But at the moment I could buy all Auburn street,
但F在我可以I下整lAuburn street
take the Phoenix club and turn it into my ping-pong room.
把P凰俱凡扛某晌业钠古仪蚴
I'll let you know how the party is.
我告V你派Φ那榭
We recognise that you're a plaintiff in one suit involving Facebook
你是@起Facebook案子VA的原告
and a witness in another.
和另一起VA的C人
Yes, sir.
是的  先生
At any time in the weeks prior to Mark telling you his idea,
在Markc你分享@意的前字苎Y
did he mention Tyler Winklevoss, Cameron Winklevoss,
他提到^Tyler Winklevoss  Cameron Winklevoss
Dedre Revedra or Harvard Connection?
Dedre Revedra或哈佛Wj
Yes,
f^
he said they asked him to work on their site.
他f他他去建W站
But that he looked at what they had
但他看^他的成果後
and decided it wasn't worth his time.
X得那就是浪M他的rg
He said even his most pathetic friends
他f  就算他最菜的朋友
knew about getting people interested
也比@群砘锴
in the website than these guys.
更能W站吸引大\眼球
These guys means my clients?
@群砘锸侵肝业漠事人
Yes.
是
He resented, Mark resented that they...
他很不爽  Mark很不爽他...
your clients thought
因你的事人f
that he needed to rehabilitate his image after Facemash.
他需要在Facemash後恢托蜗
Mark didn't want to rehabilitate anything with Facemash.
Mark]想在Facemash後挽回什麽
Hacked into the Harvard computers,
他黑M了哈佛的XWj
he blew his nose at the add-board.
蛩Ａ诵姓委T
He got a lot of notoriety.
名四起
Facemash did exactly what he wanted to do.
他所期待的|西  都通^FacemashF了
Were you aware that while Mr. Zuckerberg was buliding the"The Facebook"
那你是否清楚在Zuckerberg先生建立The Facebook的^程中
he was also communictaing with the plaintiffs?
他一直c原告保持著M呢
Not at the time I wasn't, but...
r不知道  但...
It really did not have much to do with the Winklevoss dating site.
它跟Winklevoss的交友W站]什麽干S
How would you know, you weren't even there.
你怎麽知道  你根本就不在
Were you aware that while Mr. Zuckerberg
那你是否知道在Zuckerberg先生
was building the "The Facebook",
建立The Facebook的^程中
he was leading the plaintiffs
他想原告J
to believe he was building the Harvard Connection.
他在建立哈佛Wj工作
Conclusion not found in evidence.
你的Y]有C
We are about to find the evidence.
接下砭褪亲C
From Mark Zujerburg to Tylor Winklevoss, November 30, 2003,
2003年11月30日  Mark ZujerburgoTylor Winklevoss的]件
I read over all the stuff you send me related to Harvard Connection,
我看了你l的所有P于哈佛Wj的Y料
and it seems like it shouldn't take to long to implement,
看起F它詹恍枰太Lrg
so we can talk about it
明晚我做好所有基本功能
after I get all the basic functionality up tommorrow night.
然後我再
From Mark Zujerburg to Tylor Winklevoss December 1, 2003.
2003年12月1日  Mark ZujerburgoTylor Winklevoss的]件
Sorry I was unreachable tonight.
抱歉今晚]接
I just got about three of your missed calls,
我看到你的三未接
I was working on a problem setted for my system collapsed.
系y崩⒘  我才一直在忙著理
From Mark Zujerburg to Tylor and Cameron Winklevoss December 10, 2003.
2003年12月10日  Mark ZujerburgoTylor和Cameron Winklevoss的]件
this week has been pretty busy
@周很忙
This week has been pretty busy,between HARVARD, classes and work."
@周一直忙于HARVARD W和工作
So I think its probably best to postpone the meeting.
我X得最好⒁面推t
I'm also really busy tommorow
我明天也很忙
OK anybody else feel like there is somethin up with this guy?
你不X得@小子有c不
Tell him OK.
告V他]}
But we do have to make sure we all meet up before we go off for break.
但我起a得在散夥前上一面（YY的。。。辛苦了。。。）
I know, I know.
好的  好的
Yeah watch out.
好  保重
Hey Mark...
Mark
I need a dedicated LINUX box running APACHE with------backend
我得I能\行APACHE的LINUX系y... （原我力o能）
Its gonna cost a little more money.
所以需要更多Y金
How much more.
要多少
About 200 hundred more
要200刀
Do we need it.
有必要
Its gotta handle the traffic.
得用它控制流量
Do it.
那I吧
I already did.
已I了
Hey guess what
你猜怎麽著
I made the secound cut.
我M入二面了
That's good.
不e
You should be proud of that right there,
@就够你自豪的了
dont worry if you dont make it any further.
]被取也o所^
I'll get out of here.
那我先撤了
From Mark Zuckerburg to Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss
Mark ZuckerburgoTyler和Cameron Winklevoss
and Divya Narendra
以及Divya Narendra
Dec 15 2003
2003年12月15日
I have a CS problem set that I am just getting started with
我_始著手建立密a系y
And it should be about 15 hours of coding so I'll be busy tommorow night.
需要花15小r砭a  所以明晚很忙
I wont really be free to meet until next wednesday afternoon.
下周三下午之前我都]rg面
I have to cancel Wednesday afternoon.
@周三下午我去不了了
I've basically been in the lab this whole time.
@段rg我一直泡D^
And I also wont be able to do staurday
本周六恐怕也不行
As I have to meet up with my parents.
我得去父母
As the plaque reads "John Harvard"
匾上刻著"John Harvard"
Founder of HARVARD UNIVERSITY in 1638.
"于1638年立哈佛大W"
Some call this the statue of 3 lies.
有人f@雕像包含了3e言
What are the 3 lies?
是哪3e言呢
MR.Dowd
Dowd先生
3 lies, first.
3e言  第一
Shit
靠
Take yor pants off.
子吧
I know.
我就知道
AH Mr.Savarin
Savarin先生
1 - Harvard was founded in 1636.
一  哈佛建立于1636年
Not 1638
不是1638年
2 - Hravard was not founded by John Harvard.
二  John Harvard不是哈佛的始人
3 - That is not John Harvard.
三  那雕像不是John Harvard
Who is it.
那是l
Freind of the scupture Daniel Chester.
雕塑家Daniel Chester的朋友
Keep your jacket on.
你不用外套了
39 days after Mr.Zucermans initial meeting with my clients.
在Zucermans先生c我的委托人初次面39天后
And he still has'nt completed work on HARVARD CONNECTION.
他]有建成HARVARD CONNECTION
But on Jan 11 2004
而在2004年1月11日
Mr.Zuckerburg registered the
Zuckerburg先生却在Network SolutionW站
domain name the FACEBOOK, by network solutions.
注册了FACEBOOK的域名
To the best of your Knowledge
就你所知
had he even begun work on HARVARD CONNECTION.
他是否著手^HARVARD CONNECTION的建立工作
Not to my knowledge.
地球人都知道
No
]有
Hey Cameron Im still a little sceptical that we
Cameron  我仍然岩
have enough fuctionality in the site to really draw the attention
我的W站功能是否S富到可以吸引
and to gain the critical mass neccessary to get a site like this to run.
足够多的用砭S持W站的持mI
Will speak soon.
以後
This is the 1st time he mentioned any problems.
@是他第一次提出}
Yes it was.
是的
You sent 36 e-mails to Mr.Zuckberg
你l送了36封]件oMr.Zuckberg先生
And received 16 e-mails in return
收到了16封回信
And this is the 1st time he indicated he was not happy.
而@是他第一次表F出消O情w
That's correct.
]e
He had 42 days to study our system and get out ahead ...
他花42天研究我的系y  然後己有
Do you see any of your code on Facebook,
Facebook上有你的a
Did I use any of your code?
我用了你的a
You stole our whole godamn idea!
你他`取了我的整理念
Fellas
老兄冷o
- How's dot com for Harvard dize.... - Can I continue with my deposition?
-（我自己都知道得不Α！！Ｔ俅o能。。。）  -我能^m述
You know you really dont need
你其根本不需要
a forensic team to get to the bottom of this
一法律小M砀闱迨
If you guys were the inventors of Facebook,
如果你非f自己是Facebook的始人
you invented FACEBOOK
那S便你
I cant wait to stand over
我迫不及待把你踩在脚下
your shoulder and watch you write us a check
看你支票o我
Bullshit
去屎吧
Let's continue
您^m
February 4, 2004
2004年2月4日
Mark?
Mark
There is a girl in your art history class named Stephanie Attis,
在你g史班上有叫Stephanie Attis的女孩
do you happen to know if she has a boyfreind
她有男朋友
Have you ever seen her with anyone?
她有和l在一起
and if not, do you happen to know if she's going to go out...
]有的  你X得她不跟我出去...
Dustin
Dustin
Mark
Mark
We were suppossed to meet at nine
f好九c的
Slept with in?
睡^^了?
Have to add a feature
得加特徵
What?
什麽
Shit,it's done it it's really good
靠  你都完成了  挺不e呀
Clean and simple
明快
No disneyland, no Live New Girls.
]有迪斯尼@  ]有影介B
Watch.
看著
What are you writing?
什麽呢
Realtionship status
PS羁
Interested in
好友P注
This is what drives life at college
@就是大W生活的中心
Are you having sex or are'nt you
有]有妞可以上
Its like people take certain classes, sit where they sit
就像  人上固定的n程  坐固定的位置
Do what they do ... want to have some center... you know
做固定的事情  去固定的俱凡  你懂的
Thats what FACEBOOK is going to be about
那就是FACEBOOK的目的
They're going to log on because after all the cake and watermelon there is a chance
他之所以登  H了找C去...
To get laid?
R子
Meet girl.
JR姑娘
Yes
]e
It's really good
太o力了
And that was it.
@泳托辛
What do you mean
什麽意思
It's ready.
已浜昧
It's ready
浜昧
Yeah
是
right now
R上
That was it
@泳托辛
Here's the masthead
@是祟^
You made a masthead
你做了祟^
Yeah
是
"Eduardo Savarin, Co-Founder and C F O
Eduardo Savarin  合始人  首席展
You have no idea what that's going to mean to my father.
你永h不知道@ξ野忠馕吨什麽
Sure I do.
我知道
Let's go online?
能上Q
Right now
F在就能
Get your laptop out
把你P本拿出
Why Why do you need my laptop
什麽用我的P本
You got emails for everybody at the "Phoenix Club"
你有Phoenix Club所有成T的]箱地址
I don't know
我想
I'm not sure if tis going to be cool that I am doing this
不知道@幼龊貌缓
Spam
l垃圾]件
This is not spam
不是垃圾]件
No I know it's not spam
是  我知道不是
If we send to our friends, its just gonna bounce around us dorks.
如果lo咱的朋友  只能在呆子g流
I have'nt got in yet
我不是正式成T呢
These guys know people.
那些人交H圈V
and I need their e-mails
我需要他的]箱
Sure
好吧
Good
好
Give me the mailing list
把M人名谓o我
"Jabberwock12 @ Harvard E-D-U."
Jabberwock12 @ Harvard E-D-U (Jabberwock是《埯z漫游仙境》中的角色)
These guys ... They're literary geniuses
@些砘  拿自己文W天才
They're obvious Lewis Carroll's references?
是《埯z漫游仙境》是以他原型?
They're not so bad
他人挺好的
I'm just saying
ff而已
Yeah your right
S你便吧
Sites live.
W站_通了
Lets go get a drink and celebrate.
去喝一杯c祝一下吧
I'm buying
我I
Mark?
Mark
Are you praying?
你在\告
What ever happened to Cole Porter and Irving Berlin ?
什麽不唱科?波特和艾文?伯林的歌(都是美著名作曲家)
Valentine's Day.They're playing love songs
今天是情人  然要唱情歌
Good point.
f得好
Cause Cole Porter and Irving Berlin Never wrote any love songs
就好像他z都]^情歌似的
Honey you should put your laptop away
H鄣  e再玩P本了
Seven differnt people spamming the same link.
七人o我l了同一W站地址
AKC?
美B狗俱凡浚
What is it?
是什麽
I don't know.
不知道
But I'm really hoping it's cats that looks like Hitler.
不^最好又是L得像希特勒的猫
I could never get enough of that
我也看不够
No, it's not.
不是
Here?
质谗
What?
怎麽了
Hey what is wrong
出什麽事了
It's fine.
]事
Not now
F在]空
Need 20 minutes
再等20分
OK, I just want to let you know that Zuckerberg stole our website
我只想告V你Zuckerberg`取了咱的W站
Mark Zuckerberg he stole our web site
Mark Zuckerberg`取了咱的W站
It's been live for more then 36 hours
已_通36小r了
Mr. Hotchkiss
Hotchkiss先生
lawyer, from dad
父H的律
Im here with my brother Tylor and business partner
我F在和Tylor以及一生意合夥人在一起
Welcome to the "TheFacebook"
g迎淼Facebook
"TheFacebook" is an online directory
Facebook是j不同人HWj的
to connect with different social networks
W上姓名簿
Must have an Harvard .EDU adress to register
你必用Harvard .EDU]箱碜⒉
That's right , yes sir
]e  先生
I called earlier. Im looking for Mark Zuckerberg
我才打^  我找Mark Zuckerberg
Yes, sir he actually quoted in
笊嫌幸欢嗡的引言
I read it to you
我xo您
Everyone is talking alot about Universal FACEBOOK within HARVARD
哈佛Y的所有人都在宇宙FACEBOOK
I think it's kind of silly that it would
我X得要花啄甑rg
take the university a couple of years to get around to it
碜龀蛇@件事直傻到家了
I can do a classier job then they can
我能比他做得更漂亮
and I did it.
而且我做到了
- Tell him it's Divya Narendra called. - I don't know. That's how he talked.
-告V他是Divya Narendra打淼  -不知道  @是他f的
As of yesterday evening, Zuckerberg said
Zuckerbergf  巫蛱煲煌
that over 650 students registered to use the Facebook.Com,
就有超^650名W生在Facebook上注册
He said that he anticipated 900 would join by this morning
他Ay截至今天早晨人⑦_到900
Yes,he was just reading that
他x到  第一天就有
650 students signed up for it on the 1st day
650名W生注册了
God If I was a drug dealer,
天呐  如果我是毒
I could not give free drugs to 650 people in a day
我才不在一天Yo650人免M派l毒品
This guy doesn't have 3 freinds to rub together to make a fourth
@砘锼Φ袅巳和他分t的朋友（。。。不懂）
All right yes thts what well do Mr.Hotchkiss
好的  就@  Hotchkiss先生
we'll put it all together and well e-mail it to you
我整理好材料就l]件o您
You wont be able to go on the web site yourself
您o法H自登W站
Because you dont have a ... Harvard ...
因您]有哈佛]箱
You know it would just be easier for us to email it to you
是我lo您更方便
I'm sure You're right, he is a good guy
您f的]e  他是好人
And hes very bright and Im sure he didnt mean to...
他很明  而且我相信他不是故意要...
What he did
要@麽做的
Well thank you very much and dad...
十分感x您和父H
I love too.
我也勰
This is a good guy?
他是好人?
We don't know that hes not a good guy
我不知道他不是好人
We know he stole our idea
他`取了咱的想法
We know he lied to our faces for a month and a half
而且面撒e  _了咱一半月
NO.He never lied to our face
不  他]面撒e
OK he never saw our faces fine.
他根本]露^
He lied through our e-mail accounts
他一直用]件_咱
And he gave himself a 42 day head start
而且自己先了42天
Because he knows and apparently you dont
因他清楚  占先C者王
Which is that getting there first is everything
而@一c你根本就不懂
I'm a competitve racer Dave I dont think you
我是跑健  Dave
need to school me on the importance of getting there first
不用┠憬涛蚁C的重要性
Thank-you
xx
All right
好吧
That was your father's lawyer?
那是你父H的律
He is our counsel
他是咱的法律
He is going to look at all this and if he
他查看所有@些Y料
thinks its appropriate, hes going to send a cease and desist letter
如果必要  他l送勒令停止通知函
Whats that gonna do
@是质谗
What you want to hire an IP lawyer and sue him?
你想雇知Rb喾矫娴穆控告他？
No, I want to hire the SOPRANOS to beat the shit out of him with a hammer
不  我想雇整黑道家族去把他菊花打
We dont have to do that
]那必要
Thats right
理智
We can do that ourselves
我自己邮
I m 6.5 220 and theres 2 of me
我堂堂七尺男  是p份的
Well whatever Im saying lets
我f  大家都冷o下
calm down until we know what were talking about
再接下淼氖
How much more information are you waiting for
你找什麽其他信息
We met with Mark 3 times, we exchanged 52 e-mails
我^Mark三次  通^52封]件
we can prove that he looked at the code what is that on the bottom of the page
我能C明他看到了面底部的a
That's Mark Zuckerberg production
那是Mark Zuckerberg做的
On the home page?
主上的?
On every page.
所有面上的都是
Shit, I need a second to let the ...
（不懂 貌似是他很震@  想有rg冷o一下之的。。。）
They wrote Zuckerberg said he hoped the privacy option would help
笊著Zuckerbergf  他希望[私x可以
restore his reputation following student out rage over Facemash.Com
椭他恢鸵FacemashW站而一落千丈的u
Exactly what we said to him
@是咱跟他f的
He's giving us the finger in the Crimson
他@是在公然挑
While we are waiting for dads lawyer to
在父H的律看@些材料的r候
look this stuff over we can get something going in the paper
我可以弄出c屿o蠹
No
不可以
People know that this is in dispute
大家知道出y子了
We're not starting a knife fight in the Crimson
我不武力威{他
We're not suing anybody.
也不控告他
Why not
什麽
I don't understand. Why not
是呀  什麽
He's gonna say stupid
他笑我
Me?
我?
Say it, why not?
f呀  什麽
Because we are gentlemen of Harvard
因我是哈佛的士
This is Harvard, were you
@Y是哈佛
dont plant stories, and you dont sue people
你不So事生非  也不S控告他人
You thought he was gonna be the only one that thought that was stupid?
你X得只有他笑你?
During the time when you say you had this idea
在你Q你有了@想的r候
Did you know Tylor and Cameron, came for a family of means?
你是否知道Tylor和Cameron家境殷
A Family of means?
什麽意思
Did you know their father was wealthy?
你是否知道他的父H很富有
I not sure why your asking me that
我不明白你@质谗
It's not important that you be sure why I am asking
你明白c否不重要
Not important to you
δ碚f不重要
Sy.
Sy
Did you know that they came from money?
你知道他家很富裕
I had no idea weather they came from money or not
我不清楚他家是否很富裕
In one of your e-mails to Mr. Narendra,
在你loNarendra先生的一封]件Y
you referenced Howard Winklevoss consulting firm
你提到了Howard Winklevoss咨公司
If you say so
你f有就有吧
Howard Winklevoss founded a firm whose assets are of hundreds of millions
Howard Winklevossk了一家碛|fYb的公司
You also knew Tyler and Cameron were
你也知道Tyler和Cameron是哈佛
members of the Harvard final club called The Porcellian
F族W生社FThe Porcellian的成T
You pointed that out
你f的]e
Excuse us for inviting you in
真z憾初竟然邀你M
To the bike room
M了停室
So its safe to say that you were aware that my clients had money
所以可以得出  你知道我的委托人很富有
Yes
是的
Let me tell you why I am asking,
F在我告V你提此的原因
I'm wondering why if you knew you needed a thousand dollars
我在想  若你需要一千美金kWj公司
for an internet venture you didnt ask my clients for
何不向我的委托人で筚Y金椭
they had demonstrated an interest in that kind of thing.
而他@然υI域是很感d趣的
I asked my best friend for the
我我最好的朋友出的X
money because thats who I wanted to be partners with
他才是我想要合作的人
Eduardo was the President of the Harvard
Eduardo是哈佛投Yf的主席
Investers Association, and he was also my best friend
也是我最好的朋友
Your best friendis suing you for six hundred million dollars
可你最好的朋友F在要你r6|美元
I didnt know that tell me more
我不清楚@事  fc
Eduardo,what happened after the initial launch?
Eduardo  在W站初次\I後l生了什麽
Im Sorry Sy, would you mind adrssing him as Mr. Savarin?
抱歉Sy  您Q呼他Savarin先生
Gretchen they're best freinds
Gretchen  他是好朋友
Not anymore
不再是了
We already went through this never mind ...
我^@了  算了
Mr. Savarin, what happened after the initial launch
Savarin先生  W站初次\I後情况怎
It exploded
一Q@人
Every body on Campus was using it.
W校Y所有人都上
Facebook me,
加我Facebook
it was a common expression after two weeks.
芍茚峋统闪肆T表_
And Mark?
Mark呢
And Mark was the biggest thing on the campus?
Mark成了校@L人物
That included 19 Nobel laureates
Facebook上有十九位Z得主
and 15 Pulitzer Prize winners,
十五位普利策得主
two future Olympians and a movie star.
晌晃淼W\明星  和一影明星
Who is the movie star?
影明星是l
Does it matter?
@有PS
No.
]
It was a beautiful day, and I was in my Radcliffe dorm room.
那天天馇缋  我在宿舍房gY
He brought that magzine up and he showed it to me,
他拿起s志o我看
and he said,"Look, it's not gonna happen without us."
他f  ]有我就]有@
We've gotta start now.
F在就得_始
And I said,"OK."
然後我f  好啊
Let's be basic out there.
f回
Now most of you may be thinking the rest of the story.
F在你可能都在想故事的Y局
Believe it or not,
不管你信不信
At the beginning of this industry, we were very humble.
@件事_始的r候  我都很低{
The kit computer on the cover of that magazine...
s志封面上的那套X
had an 8080 processor in it.
有8080理器
Once you paid an extra for a 1 ? memory board,
如果你多I一却l
you've got 256 Bytes.
就多256字
So the challenge when I wrote Basic,
所以BasicZ言r
it wasn't just to run it at 4K bytes,
}不在于以4KB\行
but, I always have to leave the room for the users
而是  我得用
to run the programms, at 4K bytes.
以4KB跑程序留出足够的空g
Your friend, is that Mark Zuckerberg?
你的朋友  是Mark Zuckerberg
Yeah.
是的
He made the "Facebook"?
是他建了Facebook
I mean, it's both of us. It's our...we're...Yeah. We...yes.
我是f  我  我  是的
Cool. I am Christy Lee, this is Alice.
酷  我是Christy Lee  @是Alice
Very nice to meet you.
很高dJR你
Facebook me when you get home.
回去加我Facebook
Maybe we can go and grab a drink.
我出去喝妆怎麽
Yeah. Certainly. Absolutely.
好啊  ]}  可以
She said, Facebook me.
她f  加我Facebook
Then the next second is that we can all go out for a drink.
下一句就是我可以出去喝一杯
This is so great.
@太棒了
For 2 reasons.
有理由
First because she said Facebook,
第一是因她提到了Facebook
and the other,
另一原因是
They want to have drinks later.
他想之後去喝酒
Have you ever heard so many
你以前知道
good things packed into one regular sized sentence.
一句普普通通的可以包括@麽多好事
Excuse me, Mark?
Σ黄  是Mark
Yeah.
嗯
I am Stewart Singer.
我是Stewart Singer
I'm in your OS class.
和你一起上操作系yn
Sure.
哦
Awsome job with the Facebook.
你做的Facebook真了不起
Awsome job.
了不起
Thanks.
xx
I'm Bob.
我是Bob
How are you doing?
你好
You know, I can swear he was looking at you.
知道  他f下一比w茨
When he said "The next Bill Gates could be right in this room",
可能就在@g屋子Y  他肯定看的是你
I doubt it.
我表示岩
I showed up late I didnt even know who the speaker was
我硗砹  我根本不知道演v者是l
It was Bill Gates.
比?w茨
Sure, that makes sense.
是啊  @就f得通了
Alright, thanks guys.
好了  xx你
Are you a moron?
你是白痴
Time to monetize the thing.
是r候套F了
What were their names?
她叫什麽碇
You hear what I just said?
我才f什麽了
What?
什麽
I said it's time to monetize the site.
我fW站可以_始套F了
What does that mean?
什麽意思
It means, its time for the web site to start generate revenue.
我的意思是  W站F在可以_始盈利了
I know the word, I am asking how you want to do it.
我知道那~  我是你想怎麽F
Advertising.
V告
No.
不行
Well we got 4000 members.
我F在有四千名用袅
Because Facebook is a cool,
因Facebook很酷
And if we start selling pop-ups for Mountain Dew...
如果我出百事激浪的V告
Well I wasn't thinking Mountain Dew,
我不是f百事激浪之的
but at some point I am talking as the business end of the company.
我是想f公司的主要I
We don't even know what it is yet.
我不知道主要I帐鞘谗崮
We don't know what it is.
我不知道是什麽
We dont know what it can be,
我不知道能是什麽
We don't know what it will be, we know that it's just cool.
也不知道是什麽  我只知道很酷
that is a priceless assets I'm not giving up.
@是我不放弃的or之
So when will it be finished?
什麽r候是^呢
It won't be finished.
不Y束的
That's the point, the way fashions never finishes.
就是@  像r尚永不消亡一
Fashion,
r尚
fashion is never finished.
r尚永h不Y束
You're talking about fashion? Really, you...
你在r尚  有]有搞e
I'm talking about the idea and I'm saying that it's never finished.
我在f我的想法  它不停止的
OK, they manage to make money selling pants.
好  r尚就是uu子赍X
Mark, what is this?
Mark  @是什麽
A what?
什麽
This.
@
It's called a Cease and Desist letter.
@是停止和中嗝令
What were their names?
她的名字是什麽
Who?
l
The girls.
那些女孩
When did you get this?
你什麽r候拿到@的
About ten days ago, right after we launched the site.
大概十天前  W站上Q之後那天晚上
Jesus Christ!
天哪
Hey, the girls,
喂  那些女孩
what were their names?
她的名字是什麽
They're saying the Winklevoss twins,
是Winklevoss兄弟
are saying that you stole their ideas.
他f你抄u他的想法
I find that to be a little more than mildly annoying.
我X得@就是小打小[
They find it to be intellectual property theft.
他J@是知Rb嘭飧`行
Why didn't you show this to me?
你怎麽]把@o我看
It was adressed to me.
是o我的
They're saying that we stole the
他f我
Facebook from David Neandra and the Winklevoss twins.
David Neandra和Winklevoss兄弟那剽`了Facebook
I know what it says.
我知道他f什麽
Did we?
我剽`了
Did we what?
我剽`什麽
Don't screw around with me now.
F在就e糊弄我了
Look at me.
我f
The letter says we could face legal action.
信上f我面R法律VA
No, it says I could face legal action.
不  它f的是我面R法律VA
This is from a lawyer, Mark,
@是律函  Mark
they must feel they have some grounds.
他肯定有什麽C
The lawyer is their father's house counsel.
那律是他爸爸的企I法律
Do they have grounds?
他有C
The grounds are our thing is cool and popular,
C就是我的W站又酷又t火
and "Harvard Connection" is lame.
而Harvard Connection就是U物
Eduardo I didn't use any of their code,
Eduardo  我]有抄u他的代a
I promise I didn't use anything.
我l誓  我]抄u任何|西
Look, a guy who builds a nice chair,
著  做出了一把漂亮椅子的人
doesn't owe money to everyone who has ever built a chair.
不欠任何以前做^椅子的人X
Look, they came to me with an idea...
他е一想法碚椅
I had a better one.
我想出了更好的
Why didn't you show me this letter?
你什麽不o我看@封信
I didn't think it was a big deal.
我X得]什麽大不了的
Is there something wrong?
出什麽}了
If there's ever anything wrong,
如果有任何}
you can tell me.
你都可以告V我
I'm the guy that wants to help.
我提供椭的
This is our thing.
@是我的事
Now is there anything that you need to tell me?
F在你有什麽想告V我的了
No.
]有
What are we doing about this?
我@是在质谗
I went to 3L Student Legal Services,
我去了3LW生法律服詹
and they told me to write them back.
他我回信
And what did you say?
你f了什麽
When we met in January,
我一月面的r候
I expressed my doubts about the site.
我f了我W站的岩
Where it stood with graphics.
@有D解
How much programming was left that I had not anticipated.
我]料到有那麽多事情要做
Lack of hardware, we had website use and promotion,
硬P不够  W站使用和推V
and the to go on to successfuly launch the web site.
有W站的成功\行
This is your first time, you raised any of those concerns, right?
@是你第一次P注@些
I raised concerns before.
我以前也P注^
Bullshit.
扯淡
That's all gentlemen.
大家士一c
I'm talking about the meeting in January
我在f一月的那次面
to which this letter is refering.
@封信Y提到的
Yeah.
是的
Let me rephrase this,
我重申一下
you sent my client sent 16 e-mails.
你o我的客舭l了十六封子]件
The first 15, you didn't raise any concerns.
前十五封Y  你都]有提到^那些}
Is that a question?
有}
In the 16th email you raised concerns about site functionality.
第十六封Y你提到了W站\I}
Were you leading them on for six weeks?
你m了他六星期
No.
]有
Then why didn't you raise any of these concerns before ...
那什麽你以前]提到^
It's raining.
下雨了
I'm sorry.
Σ黄
It just started raining.
_始下雨了
Mr. Zuckerberg, do I have your full attention?
Zuckerberg先生  你在我f
No.
]有
Do you think I deserve it?
你X得你
What?
什麽
Do you think I deserve your full attention?
你X得你放c注意力在我身上
I had to swear an oath before I began this deposition
在作C之前我得宣誓
and I don't want to perjure myself.
我不想`背自己的誓~
So I have a legal obligation to say no.
所以我必f不
OK no.
好吧
You don't think I deserve your attention.
你X得自己]必要注意我
I think if your clients want to sit on my shoulders
我X得如果你的委托人想要踩在我肩膀上
and call themselves tall, they have a right to.
自Q自己很高  那完全可以
But there is no requirement
但詹皇钦f
that I enjoy sitting here, listening to people lie.
我就得坐在@  享受人的e言
You have part of my attention, you have the minimum amount.
我放一c注意力在你身上  就一c
The rest of my attention is back at the offices of Facebook.
其它的我要用硐胛业Facebook
When my colleagues and I were doing things,
我和同事工作的r候
that no one in this room including and especially your clients,
@g屋子Y的人  尤其是你的委托人
are intellectually or creatively capable of doing.
都]有能力和造力碜鱿嗤的事
Does that adequately answer your condescending question?
@些能回答你自以是的}了
I have 12:45, why don't we say that's lunch.
十二c四十五了  我吃午怎麽
Back at two thirty.
牲c半回
So, what were their names?
那  她叫什麽名字
Their names were Christy and Alice.
是Christy和Alice
And they want to have drinks tonight.
她想今晚喝一杯
I don't care.
我不在乎
Hey man sorry, a couple of girls are freshening up in there.
夥  Σ黄  那有妞在打扮呢
Ok.
好吧
We have groupies.
我有狂岱劢z了
I'll be right back.
我R上回
Where are you going?
你去哪
Erika?
Erika
Hi.
嗨
I saw you from over there, I didn't know you came to this pub.
我哪沁看你了  我不知道你磉@了
First time.
第一次
Mine too, can I talk to you alone for a second?
我也是  能为和你聊聊
I think I'm good right here.
我X得在@f挺好
I just...
我只是
I love to talk to you alone.
我想和你为f
If we could talk outside...
如果我能去外面f
Right here is fine.
就在@挺好
I don't know if you heard about this new website I launched?
你f我做的那新W站了
No.
]有
The Facebook?
Facebook
You called me bitch on the internet, Mark.
你在W上f我是婊子  Mark
That's why I wanted to talk to you.
@就是什麽我想和你
On the internet
在W上
That is why I came over.
@就是什麽我^砹
Comparing women to farm animals?
把女人比喻成家畜
I didn't end up doing that.
我]有一直那
Didn't stop you from writing it.
可你已了
It's as if every thought
@就好像
that tumbles through your head is so clever,
你X子Y蹦出淼拿想法都那麽明
it would be a crime for it not to be shared.
如果不拿出矸窒淼脑  就是犯罪
The internets not written in pencil, Mark.
互W可不是想改就改的  Mark
It's written in ink.
是留下痕迹的
And you published that "Erika Albright" is a bitch.
你l布了Erika Albright是婊子
Right before you made an ignorant crack about my families name,
白痴地把我的姓和罩杯都搞e了
and bra size, and then rated women based on their hotness.
根女人的崂背潭冉o她打分
Erika, is there a problem?
Erika  出什麽}了
No, there's no problem.
不  ]事
You write your snide bullshit from a dark room,
你在小黑屋Y你的狗屁S刺
because of what's the angry doing nowadays.
就是了今天砺我l火的
I was nice to you.
我以前δ愫芎
Don't torture me for it.
e折磨我了
If we could just go somewhere for a minute.
如果我能去e的地方呆追昼
I do not want to be rude to my friends.
我不想放我朋友子
Ok.
好吧
Good luck with your video games.
祝你的子游蜃龅瞄_心
Yeah, that was great.
是啊  不e
That was the right thing to do to apologize, right?
你去道歉  做得很
We have to expand,
我得U大
Tommorow.
明天
Is he mad about something?
他在什麽事生
OK, we are expanding to Yale and Columbia.
我要把U大到耶和哥比
Dustin, I want you to share the coding work with me.
Dustin  我想和你一起做程工作
Chris, you are in charge of publicity and outreach,
Chris  你宣骱I胀卣
and you can start by getting us a story
可以先波士D大WW生
in the B.U. Student Newspaper.
l一篇P于我的
The Bridge.
?
They hate doing stories about Harvard.
他不意Ч佛的事
Somebody at the newspaper
笊缈隙ㄓ腥
will be a computer science major, tell him
是W算CI的  告V他
Mark Zuckerberg will do ten hours of free programming.
Mark Zuckerberg意免Mo他程十小r
Why do you want a story in the BU newspaper?
你什麽想要BU你
Because I do.
我就是想
Now here's the arrangement.
下面是具w安排
Eduardo is CFO, owns 30% of the company.
Eduardo是湛O  有30%的份~
Dustin is a vice president and head of programming,
Dustin是副裁  程
and his 5% of the company will come from my end.
我o他出5%的份~
Chris is director of publicity, and his compensation
Chris是詹块L  他的工Y
will depend on the amount of work he ends up doing.
取决于他做了多少工作
Any questions?
有什麽}
Who are these girls?
@些女孩是l
Sorry, they are Christy and Alice.
不好意思  她是Christy和Alice
Hi.
嗨
Hello.
你好
Is there anything we can do?
我能做c什麽
No.
]有
Nothing.
什麽也]有
Yale and Columbia.
耶和哥比
And Stanford.
有斯坦福
What?
什麽
Stanford.
斯坦福
It is time for them to see us from Palo Alto.
我在帕_阿托露了[近矽谷]
You don't want any lunch?
你不吃午了
No.
不吃了
You're welcome to some salad.
你可以睃c沙拉
No, thank you.
不用  xx
This must be hard.
肯定很Dy吧
Who are you?
你是l
I'm Marilyn Delpei,
我是Marilyn Delpei
I introduced myself...
我自我介B^了
I mean what do you do?
我是f你碜鍪谗
I am a secoud-year associate at the firm.
我是公司的初助理
My boss wanted me to sit in on the deposition case.
我的老我代理@件案子
What are you doing?
你在质谗
Checking to see how its going in Bosnia.
看看在波斯尼大W怎麽恿
Bosnia.
波斯尼大W
Ther don't have roads but they have Facebook?
他都]W  能上Facebook
You must really hate the Winklevoss's?
你肯定很痛恨Winklevoss兄弟
I don't hate anybody.
我不痛恨任何人
The Winklevoss are sueing me for intellectual property theft.
Winklevoss兄弟指控我剽`知Rb
They're sueing me because for the first time in their lives,
他告我  是因他L@麽大
things didn't work out the way they were supposed to for them.
第一次事c`
He is expanding.
他在U
What?
什麽
He is expanding to Yale, Columbia and Stanford,
他U展到耶  哥比和斯坦福
it's gonna be in the Crimson tommorow.
明天就能U展到研究生院了了
Really?
真的
Yeah.
是啊
Well, it looked like the Cease and Desist order
哈  似乎停止和中嗝令
really scared the shit out of him, huh.
真的把他破了
I want to hire a lawyer
我想聘一律
to file for injuctive relief, the site taken down now.
署禁制令  W站R上就倒了
Every minute the site is up,
他的W站每天都在成L
Harvard Connection becomes less valuable.
Harvard Connection越碓]r值了
I want an injuction, I want damages,
我想要禁制令  我想搞破
I want punitive release.
我想施土P
I want him dead.
我想他死
Yeah I want those things, too.
是啊  我也想
Then why aren't we doing anything about it.
那我什麽不行悠砟
Because we are gentlemen at Harvard?
因我是哈佛的士
Because you're not thinking about how it's gonna look.
因你不知道事情成什麽
How's it gonna look?
怎麽
Like my brother and I are in skeleton costumes
就像我兄弟穿著骷tb
chasing the karate kid around a high school gym.
在高中w育^Y追著空手道小子跑砼苋
Cam.
Cam
He has violated Massachusets state law.
他`反了R_T塞州的法律
He goes to Connecticut, New York,
他去康涅狄格  ~s
and to California, he will have violated Federal Law.
有加利福尼  他`反邦法律
By the way he's in violation of Harvard law.
而且他`反了哈佛校
There's no such thing as Harvard law.
可]有哈佛校@N|西
Yeah.
α
There is.
有的
Harvard student hand book.
哈佛W生手册
Every freshman is issued one of these.
每新生都有一本
Some where in this book,
@Y面f
it says you can't steal from another student.
不能偷其他W生的|西
This is what we need.
@正是我需要的
We're going to Summers.
我去找Summers校L
You can't get a meeting with Larry Summers.
你不能和Larry Summers面
My brother and I, we pay tuition at this school.
我弟弟和我  我交了WM
We carry a 3.9 GPA in this school.
我的c有3.9呢
We won trophys for this school,
我oW校A砹霜杯
and will be rowing in the Olympics for this school.
代表W校⒓W林匹克划艇比
I want a meeting with the godamn president of this school.
我他想@W校的校L
Why Stanford?
什麽是斯坦福
Why do you think...
你X得呢
Sorry,
Σ黄
I'm late for Bio-Chem.
我上生化n要t到了
Ok.
好吧
You don't know my name, do you?
你不知道我的名字  Π
Is it Stanford?
是斯坦福
I should just kick your ass.
真你去死
How do you go to a party?
你和l一起去派
Amelia Ritter.
Amelia Ritter
but you prefer Amy
但你更喜gAmy@名字
You from Olinda
你碜Olinda
Your fathers in commercial real estate and your mothers never sober.
父H是商品房N商  母H是酒鬼
What's my major?
我的I
Trombone.
吹喇叭
Really.
少
I don't know there's something about a trombone.
吹喇叭＜矣惺谗岵缓玫
French.
法Z
Your major's French.
你W法Z的
Mine?  I don't have one.
我啊  什麽I都不是
Not picking a major?
]x
I don't go to school.
]上W
You kidding
_玩笑吧
No.
]有
Where did you go to school?
那你在哪念^
William Taft Elementary.
William Taft小W
For a little while.
在那待^一段rg
Seriously.
J真c好不好
You're not like 15 years old or anything are you?
e跟我f你才十五q什麽的
You're not like 15 are you?
你也不是吧
No.
不是
So what do you do?
你到底致锏
I am an entrepreneur
企I家
Your unemployed.
失I家吧
I wouldn't say that
我可]那诱f
What would you say
你f的什麽
That I'm an entrepreneur.
我是企I家
Well, then what was your entrepreneur?
好吧  那你是质谗岬钠I家呢
Well I founded an Interent company.
我建了一家互W公司
that lets folks download and share music for free
可以大家免M下d以及分享音
Kind of like Napster?
像{普斯特那拥
Exactly like Napster.
就是{普斯特
What do you mean?
什麽
I founded Napster.
是我立了{普斯特
Sean Parker founded Napster.
拜托  是Sean Parker立了{普斯特
Nice to meet you.
正是鄙人
You're Sean Parker?
你是Sean Parker
UH HUH you see the shoes on the other.
啊哈  你看到鞋子了在另一
foot.
脚
table.
桌子
I just slept with Sean Parker?
我睡了Sean Parker
You just slept on Sean Parker?
]e  你至Sean Parker
You're a billionaire
你是|f富翁
Not technically.
栏碇v不是
What are you?
那你是
Broke.
破b者
There's not a lot of money in free music
做免M音瓴涣硕嗌馘X
and even less if your being sued by anyone whos won a grammy.
尤其是被那些格R美@者起V後就更寒酸了
This is blowing my mind.
所未
I appreciate that.
很高d你@诱f
I gotta hop in the shower and get ready for class
我得so洗澡  渖险n
Even though your a french major whose name is Amy.
你名字叫做Amy  I是法Z
You passed.
算你^P
I'm a hard worker.
我很好W
There's juice there's anything else you can find, help yourself
@河泄汁  有其它一些什麽  你自便吧
Mind if I check my e-mail
介意用你X查下]件
Yeah go ahead
]}
Amy Amy
Amy Amy
- Can you come out here?  - Just a second.
-能出硪幌  -等
There's a snake in here, Amy.
有l蛇  Amy
What? Where
什麽 在哪
OK there is no snake but I need to ask you something.
e心  ]蛇  想c事情才出此下策
Are you kidding me I could have been killed.
_什麽玩笑  差c要了我的命
How
怎麽
By running too fast and getting twisted in the curtain.
跑急了 差c被窗O倒
What do you need to ask me?
什麽事情非得我
I went to check my e-mail
我想查]件
and theres a website open on your computer
Y果lF上面登著一W站
Yeah after you passed out last night I went on the Facebook for a bit.
嗯  昨晚你精疲力竭之後我去Facebook上玩了
What's that?
那是什麽玩意
The Facebook?
Facebook
Stanford'S had it for like 2 weeks now
引M斯坦福快Y拜了吧
It's really awsome, freakishly addictive.
上面真的很好玩  O易上a
Seriously I'm on the thing like 5 times a day.
我每天都要上去五次
Mind if I send myself an e-mail
介意我l封]件
Yeah is everything okay
]}
Everything's great
一切都很棒
I just need to find you Mark Zuckerberg
我只想找到你  Mark Zuckerberg
Ever been in this building before
以前]磉^@
This buildings a hundred years older then the country its in.
@潜让的v史要L一百年
So do be careful
所以心c
Were sitting in chairs.
我老老坐著呢
Yes
好的
Very good
很好
You can go in now
可以M去了
Catherine, I've got students now,
Catherine  我@砹W生
students undergraduates
W生 在校生
don't know,from the looks of
不知道  不^乃的扮相砜
it they want to sell me a Brooks Brothers suit.
貌似想向我推NBrooks Brothers西服
Good morning
上午好
Good morning, sir
上午好  先生
I'm Cameron Winklevoss, this is my brother Tyle.
我是Cameron Winklevoss  @是我弟弟Tyle
Are you here because?
你磉@菏
I'm sorry sir, I thought you were reading the letter.
抱歉先生  我以您是在x信
Read the letter.
x完了
Well, we came up with an idea
是@拥  我之前有了一想法
for a website called "Harvard Connection"
建一叫作哈佛互的W站
we've since changed the name to CONNECTU.
後砀CONNECTU
And Mark Zuckerberg stole that idea and
然而Mark ZuckerbergI用了@想法涨
I understand
明白
and I'm asking what you want me to do about it?
那你想我怎麽做呢
Well, sir
好的  先生
In the HARVARD student handbook which is distributed to each freshman
在哈佛每年lo新生的W生手册中
Under the heading standars of conduct in the HARVARD community
在哈佛W生社F管理室徽轮
it says the college expects all the students to be honest
明_表明W校期望每W生都能\守信
and forthcoming in their dealings with members in the community
赵陔S後c社F成T的交往中
stundents are required to respect public and private ownership
得尊重公\及私人b
and instances of theft, missappropriation...
τ谕蹈`  不合情理的行
Anne?
Anne
Yes sir?
在
Punch me in the face, go ahead.
揍我一拳  你^m
or
或者
or unauthorised use will result in disciplinary action
或者未S可的使用予以相分
including required withdrawl from the college.
包括_除W籍
You memorised that instead of doing what
你背出那麽一大段想f明什麽
What my brother came and I came here to ask you respectfully
我和弟弟磉@菏了重地求您
Sir its against university rules to steal from other students
先生  I`@N行有悖于W校的t制度
plain and simple
非常明@
Have you spoken to your housemaster?
跟宿舍管理T反映^
Yes sir.
有的  先生
And the housemaster made a recommendation to the AD BOARD but the AD BOARD wont hear us.
宿舍管理T建h我向AD BOARD投V可AD BOARD不予交涉
Have you tried dealing with the other student directly?
你^跟另一方直接交涉
Mr. Zuckerburg hasn't been responding
Zuckerburg先生在^去的Y拜Y]有
to any of our e-mails and phone calls for the last 2 weeks.
ξ的一封]件c做^回
he doesnt answer when we knock on his door at KIRKLAND
我去科克m拜L他的r候也不_T回
and the closest I've come to dealing with him face to face
我和Mark本人距x最近的面γ娼簧
when I saw him on the quad and chased him through HARVARD SQUARE.
是在院子Y碰巧看到他  然後追他
chased him?
追他
I I I saw him and I know he saw me,
我  我看到了他而且他肯定也看到了我
I went after him
所以才追的
and he disapeaared.
然後他不了
I don't see this as a universty issue.
我不J@在W校管理
Of course it's a a universty issue.
然在W校管理攘
There's a code of ethics
@可娴降赖路t
and an honor code and he violated them both.
以及su法t  而他都`犯了
you entered into a code of ethics with the university.
你cW校之g有道德契s
not with each other.
你之g]有
I'm sorry President Summers.
很抱歉  Summers校L
What you just said makes no sense to me at all.
我X得你f的o稽之
I'm devestated by that.
真令人心
What my brother means is
我弟弟的意思是
Mark Zuckerburg walked into our dorm room and stole our computer.
Mark Zuckerburg走M我室然後偷走了我的X
That would be a universty issue.
那泳褪切７揭管的了
I don't know, this office doesn't handle petty larceny.
不缘  @gk公室不是用硖理小偷小摸的
This isnt petty larceny.
@不是小偷小摸
This idea is potentialy worth millions of dollars.
@想法的潜在r值值上百f
Millions?
上百f
Yes.
]e
You might just be letting your imaginations run away with you.
你最好你的想像力跟著你一K走好了
Sir
先生
I honestly don't think your in any position to make that call
我X得身居高位不下此嗾
I was the US Treasury Secretary.
我做^政部L
I'm in some position to make that call.
我有Y格那诱f
"Letting our imagnations run away with us "
想像力伴S我成L
Is exactly what we were told to do in your Freshaman address?
那不正是您在新生演v~中所f的
well then I would suggest that you let your imaginations
]e  而F在我想建h你你的想像力
run away with you on a new project.
著力于新的意上
You would?
是
everyone at HARVARD is inventing something
哈佛的每人都在造
HARVARD undergarduates believe that inventing
哈佛在校生相信
a job is better then finding a job.
造一新的工作比找到工作更有意x
So I suggest again that
所以我再次建h
the 2 of you come up with a new new project.
你把精力放在新的意上
I'm sorry, sir. But thats not the point
抱歉  先生  您可能跑}了
Please
行吧
come right at the point.
@才是重c
You don't have to be a intellectual property expert
您不必像一位高明的＜
to understand the difference between right and wrong.
那颖ee之g的差e
You're saying that I don't?
你f我]必要
Of course I am not saying that sir.
不是那意思  先生
I'm saying that.
我就是那意思
Really?
是
Ann
Ann
How did I get this appointment?
@面是怎麽安排的
Colleagues of their father
他z父H的同事
Let me tell you something, Mr. Winklevoss, Mr. Winklevoss.
我砀嬖V你吧  Winklevoss先生cWinklevoss先生
Since your on the subject of right and wrong
你一再提及P于e的事情
This action, this meeting
@件事  @次h
The 2 of you being here, is wrong
你在@Y  就是e的
It's not worthy of Harvard,
@是哈佛所不屑的
it's not what Harvard saw in you.
@不是哈佛想在你身上看到的
You don't get special treatment.
你不搞特
We never asked ...
我]有
Wai ...Wai..Start another project
等等  您f搞新的意
Like were amking a diorama for a science fair
像在科W展上搞立w模型
If you have a problem with that Mr WinkleVoss
WinkleVoss先生  如果你有什麽}
We never asked for special treatment.
我奈匆求特殊Υ
The courts allways at your disposal.
你完全可以采取司法途
Is there anything else I can do for you.
有可以您效诘
Ty.
x了
Thank you very much for your time.
感x  叨_了
I broke a 335 year old door knob.
不小心弄牧擞腥百多年v史的T把手
Eduardo, spring break you
Eduardo  新年的r候你
and Mr. Zuckerburg took a trip to New York.
同Zuckerburg先生去了趟~s
Yes.
是的
What was the purpose of the trip?
去那做什麽
Well, as CFO I set up some meetings with potential advertisers.
呃  我以首席展俚纳矸莅才帕送潜在客舻囊面
Who paid for the trip?
l沓旅行M用
It was paid for out of the thousand dollar account I set up a few months earlier.
用@月砦易约下淼囊磺美元
At this point your thousand dollars
到那r止  那一千美元
was the only money that had been put into the company.
是投在公司上的唯一Y金
Yes.
是的
How did you feel the meetings went?
hM行得怎
Went terribly.
糟糕透了
Why?
何
Mark was asleep.
Mark老打瞌睡
I was not asleep.
我]打瞌睡
Can I repharse my answer?
可以修正下我的回答
I wish he was asleep.
我倒希望他睡著了
So were at 29 schools now with over 75000 members.
F在已覆w到二十九所大W  注册人T超^七f五千
People who go on the Facebook tend to stay on longer
去Facebook的人T性地喜g多待一
than almost any other web site.
比其它站c待得rg都要L
Now heres the most impressive statistc.
@泳陀辛巳缦麦@人的
91% of the people who try it once
百分之九十一的人第一次玩Facebook後
come back. Now if you'll allow me
就玩第二次  F在如果你允S我
Excuse me one second
打_一下
What sound is he making, is that like a tick?
他在弄什麽  滴答滴答的
Was'nt a tick
不是滴滴答
Was
而是
Like throttle sound.
喉笛Y面
Almost a gag reflex
就像咽喉反射
What is this ...
你什麽意思
There was 1 more meeting scheduled for the New York.
那次~s之行有一次h
Yes, it was a dinner.
是的  是局
It was set up through my girlfriend at the time.
是我r的女朋友安排的
Would you say that Mark was excited about this meeting
Mark@h很d^
Yes.
是的
Very.
非常d^
Their not gonna card us here right
他不把我Z出去吧
Look around
看看  有人盯著
Don't be embarrassed
eo
Tell him their not gonna card us.
跟他f他不Z我的
Their not gonna card us.
他不Z我的
Mark
Mark
Are you gonna talk about adds again.
@次你又要V告
Unless your the BALLET THEATRE of HARTFORD,
除非你是哈佛芭蕾W院的
the purpose of business is to make a profit.
做生意不就是了赍X
It isn't a business yet.
可F在]成熟
That's...that's tough for me , Its my job.
e@麽f行不行啊  @是我的事情
Never mind
e心
25 minutes late.
都^去二十五分了
He started Napster, when he was 19.
他可是{普斯特的始人  r才19q
He can be late.
他有Y格t到
He is not a God.
他又不是上帝
What is he?
那是什麽
He's 25 minutes late.
他是t到了二十五分的那人
I think you're not jealous
你不是嫉妒人家吧
I honestly wasn't jealous.
老f真]嫉妒
I was nervous.
只是o
Why?
怎麽f
I didn't know him at all.
我奈匆^他
But I had done a search and asked around and he
但之前做^{查涨宜奶打
He struck me as a kind of an....
他o我的感X是
Wildcard.
KY者
Why?
怎麽f
He crashed out of 2 pretty big Internet companies
他把杉一ヂW公司搞得倒]了
in spectacular fashion and hes got a reputation with drugs.
而公司rl展B菡好  他吸毒
He also founded the companies.
可也是他建了那杉夜司
We don't need him.
]e  所以我不需要他
He's here.
砹
I'm Sean Parker.
我是Sean Parker
How do you do.
你好
You must be Eduardo.
@位一定是Eduardo
and Christy, and Mark.
Christy  Mark
Great to meet you.
很高d到你
You guys don't have anything in front of you.
什麽都]c啊
No.
]
Tori
Tori
Hee, baby boy.
嘿
Could you bring out somethings.
可以o我睃c什麽
The laquered pork with that ginger confit
糖醋扣肉
Tuna tartar , and the lobster claws, that'll get us started.
金~大排  再睃cr  @游就可以_始了
Christy
Christy
What do you like to drink?
你喝什麽
An Appletini.
O果R提尼吧
Great.
好的
4 of those.
硭谋
From that point on it was a show of Sean.
那之後就是Sean的人秀了
The question was what did you talk about.
}是你都了些什麽
He took through his episode with NAPSTER.
他述P于{普斯特的故事
I didn't want to spend my 20's as a professinal defender.
我可不想二十q年opp就做防l者
Who knew that in the begining of 2003--
l曾想到二零零三年初
They tried to sell the company to pay the 35 million
他Du掉公司三千五百f
they said we owed in royalties
Q是我欠下的版
but I guess to them that was a little like
可我跟他v那幼鼍拖
Selling a stolen car to pay for the stolen gas.
u掉一v偷淼能偷淼钠油
So we said screw it
于是我f  去他的
and declared bankruptcy.
然後宣布破b
You made a name for yourself.
可是你却成名了
And you are dry.
你呢  ]酒了
Tory
Tory
And then he went on to his secound business venture
然後他^mv述第二次商I冒U
which was an online rolodex
是一在Q通薄
that he got thrown out of by his equity
字幕
And I wanted to do it nicely, I put on a tie
@次我想制亮c  打上I
and shined my shoes, but nobody wanted to take orders from a kid.
擦亮皮鞋  可是]人意搭理一毛^小子
So let me tell you what
所以我告V你吧
what happened through a 20 year old
一20q的毛^小子
to the top of that dot-com.
了W站成功都做了什麽
I'm not a psychiatrist,but...
我不是精神科t生  但是...
We got that on the record.
@我都知道
You're not a psychiatrist, but what?
你不是精神科t生  然後呢
A psychiatrist would say that he was paranoid.
精神科t生肯定f他是妄想症
They hired private detectives who followed you day and night.
那腿苏宜郊商饺找垢踪你
You were target for high priced escorts.
你可是高~屹p金的目巳宋
I can't prove it but I know they tapped my phone,
我]有C  但我知道他`我
so whatever it is I'm gonna trip you up. You've done already.
o用什麽招滴叶察X  我]救了
Private behaviour is a relic of a time gone by,
人行是r光所留下淼倪z迹
and somehow,someway you've
某N程度上v  我跟
managed to live your life like the DALI LAMA
_喇嘛的生活方式很像
though make shit up because
然@都是U
they don't want you, they want your idea,
但他要的不是你@人  而是你的意
and they want you to say thank you while you
而且他要在你f完"不好意思"
"excuse me",
摸摸下巴走人之後
wipe your chin and walk away.
要f上句xx
That's what happened to you?
@些都是你v^的
And delusional.
他各N臆想
But there'll be payback in case.
但他肯定不就此T手
I brought down
我已用Napster
the record companies with Napster
艨宄片公司了
and cases of their suffer seems too...
他也一定...
Sorry, you didn't bring down the record companies,
不好意思  你]艨宄片公司
They won.
他A了
In court.
官司而已
You want to buy
你想在Tower店Y[唱片店Bi]
a Tower record, Eduardo?
I唱片  Eduardo
And he told story after story about
接著他就一直v他在矽谷的生活
life in silicon valley, parties at Stanford,
在斯坦福和洛杉的⒓拥耐
down in LA, freinds who become millionaires,
有他那些成百f富翁的朋友
but mostly how Mark had to, he had to come to California...
但f的最多的是Mark一定要去加州
and then he cut around to Facebook.
最後他是f到了Facebook
So tell me about your progress.
跟我ffM展情况
Well, we're in 29 schools now,
我已Mv29大W了
we got over 75000 members.
已有75000T
Tell me about the strategy you're using.
vv你的策略
- Ok. - For intance we wanted Baylor in Texas,
-好  -就像我想M德克_斯的勒大W
but Baylor already had a social network on campus so
但勒校纫呀有Wj了
instead of going right after them,
我]有被它恐谱
we made a list of every school within a hundred miles.
而是列出了周所有的W校
Put the Facebook on those campuses first.
那些W校先可以登Facebook
Pretty soon all the Baylor kids
很快Baylor的W生
were seeing their freinds
看到他朋友都在
on our site and we were in.
我的W站上   我也就成功了
It's called the little big horn, it's smart, Mark.
@叫小巨角鹇  好c子  Mark
Thanks. That was mine.
多x  @是我想出淼
- Easy. - Hey, you know what settle an arguement for us.
-冷oc  -我z一直在
I say it's time to start
我X得考]Facebook
making money through the Facebook,
盈利的}了
Mark doesn't want to advertise.
可Mark不想做V告
Who's right?
你X得l
Neither of you yet.
你z都不
The Facebook is cool. That's what's that going for.
Facebook懒  @才是重c
You don't want to ruin it with ads, because ads aren't cool.
你不想V告Я怂  因V告太d
Exactly.
]e
It's like you're throwing the greatest party on campus,
就像你在W校⒓右特棒的晚
and someone saying it's gotta be over by 11.
但有人f11c就要Y束
That's exactly.
]e
You don't even know what the thing is yet...
你甚至不知道它究竟是什麽
how big it can get, how far it can go.
l展到什麽程度  走到多h
This is no time to put your chips down
F在rC不成熟
A million dollars isn't cool, you know what's cool?
一百f根本不算什麽  你知道多少才算
You?
是你
A Billion dollars.
十|美金
It shut everybody up.
@我都】o言
and that's what you're headed,
@也是你的目
a billion dollar evaluation.
十|美元市值
Unless you take bad advice in which case you might
也可能你采{了e`的建h之後
as well have come up with a chain of very succesful yogurt shops.
是能有成功的酸奶Bi店
When you go fishing, you can catch a lot of fish,
你去~的r候  到很多~
or you can catch a big fish.
或是一l大~
You ever walk into a guy's tendency of
你R^l喜g
a picture of him standing next to 14 trout?
和14lq~合影
No, he likes a 3000 pound marlin.
不的  他更喜g3000磅重的~
That's a good analogy.
@比喻太形象了
OK. We all know that
好吧  我都知道
marlins don't really weigh 3000 pounds, right?
~]有3000磅重的
Have you seen the big ones up close?
你近距x看^大的
No I haven't, but I don't think
]有  但我不相信
the guy holding a marlin the size of a Range Rover,
有像路虎[汽品牌]那麽大的~
that would be a really big fish and a very strong guy.
那麽大的~  人得多寻
I think you might be getting away from the point.
我X得你有c跑}了
I don't have a dog in this fight,
我@事一c都不感d趣
I'm just a fan and came to say hi.
我只是粉z一名  ^砀你打招呼
He owned Mark after that dinner.
那D之後  Mark就完全被他收I了
He picked up the check and
他I了
he told Mark that they would talk together soon,
告VMark有rg再聊
and he was gone,but not before
然後他就走了  走之前
he made his biggest contribution to the company.
公司做出了巨大的I
Drop the "The",
去掉"The"
just "Facebook". That's cool.
就叫"Facebook"吧  太棒了
Shit.
我靠
That's gotta be some kind of land-speed record for talking.
才肯定破了最短rg的o了
You want to end the party at 11.
你是想晚十一cY束
I'm trying to pay for the party.
我是在o晚I
There won't be a party,
如果一c都不的
unless it's cool.
根本就不有晚
What do you think?
你X得呢
Yeah, sure. Let's drop the "The".
然  去掉"The"吧
I meant catching the marlin
我是f我就抓那l~
instead of 14 trout.
而不是那14lq~
Doesn't that sound good?
是不是很棒
If you're a trout.
q~才@麽想
I'm going to enter this into the record: incorporation papers
接下沓侍玫氖Facebook
for Facebook and the analysis registered in Florida.
在佛_里_注册的合同文件和分析蟾
Why Florida?
什麽x穹鹆_里_
That's where my familiy lives.
我家人住在那
And ask the respondents to stipulate that
要求被告定合l款中
the articles of incorporation state the ownership as follows:
所有w偃缦
65% for Mark Zuckerberg, 30%
Mark Zuckerberg占65%
for Edurdo Severin
Edurdo Severin占30%
and 5% for Dustin Moskovitz.
Dustin Moskovitz占5%
I'll stipulate.
我提到的
And that was April 13th, 2004.
那是2004年4月13
You can mark it.
你可以把@地方圈出
Do you have anything here?
你有e的要
Yes, thank you.
是的  xx
Mr. Saverin, have you ever done anything
Saverin先生  你有]有做^
that might be considered as legitimate grounds
一些可能合同
- for termination? - No.
-K止的事情  -]有
You never did anything to
你]做^公司蒙羞
embarass the company or even seriously jeopardise it?
甚至危害公司l展的事
- No. - No?
-]有  -]有
- No. - You were accused of animal cruelty.
-]有  -你曾被控V虐待游
- Wait. - You weren't?
-等下  -
This is not happenning.
根本]有的事
Well, I have here an article from the Crimson.
我@有篇深t色校蟮奈恼
Jesus christ.
天啊
I can't have this, Eduardo.
@我接受不了  Eduardo
Oh, come on man, this is bull shit.
拜托  哥  @根本就是胡扯
This is another club playing a prank.
@是其他俱凡康鹤
I'd gotten into the Phoenix,
我加入了P凰俱凡
and been accepted as part of my initiation I had to for one
入的一任站褪
week carry with me at all times, and take care of a chicken.
要在一周r刻S身携Ш驼疹一b
They identified you as one
他J出你是Facebook的
of the founders of Facebook,
始人之一了
Jr Eduardo Severin?
小Eduardo Severin
I'm not the expert but being
我不是很I  但是
acted like torturing animals was probably bad for business.
虐待游锏男ξ的公司影很不好
I did not torture the chicken,I don't torture chickens.
我]有虐待  我不虐待的
Are you crazy?
你了
No, and settle down please.
]有  冷oc
I have here an article from the Crimson.
我@可是深t色校蟮奈恼
This is scathing.
批得特
956.
956用袅
I was having dinner at the Kirkland dining hall, with Mark and
我和Mark在Kirkland餐d吃
I had the chicken with me, because I had to have the chicken with me at all times.
我S身е  我必r刻都要е
This was college.
@就是大W的矩
Somebody is going to have to answer for this.
必得出面解@件事
969.
969了
The dining hall was serving chicken for dinner,
餐d晚餐有肉
so...and I had to feed my chicken,
所以...  我必得喂
so wha..I took little pieces of chicken and I gave it to the chicken.
所以...  我A了灼肉去喂了
Someone must have seen me because the next thing I knew,
肯定有人看到我了  接著
I was being accused of forced cannibalism.
就有人控V我吃人了
I didn't know.
我不知道
You couldn't do that.
你不那麽做的
I dealt with various animal rights groups.
我已和游嗬f解^了
I dealt with the associate dean of the college.
也和副校L解了
This was all resolved.
已]事了
988.
988了
Someone from the Porc or the Fly
就是Porc或是Fly
must have reported it,
俱凡康娜舜虻男蟾
for all I know it was the WinkleVosses.
我猜就是 WinkleVossesp胞胎值
Alright. Let's just forget about it.
好吧  不f了
This is absurd.
太可笑了
I'm being accused of animal cruelty,
我竟被控V虐待游
it's better to be accused of necrophilia.
不如f我有偈癖呢
It is better to be accused of necrophelia.
偈能好c
I'm gonna have to explain this to my father,
我得跟我爸解
I'm gonna have to explain this to everybody.
要跟大家解
What is happenning on that?
那是什麽
I have my final coming up for "Post
我"疳岷同F代g"那Tn
War and Contemporary Art", and I haven't been to class.
快Yn了  我一n都]上
I'm supposed to write about those 4 paintings.
我得u@四作品
That's a Facebook page.
那是FacebookW啊
I put it under an alias
我注册了R甲
I posted the paintings and asked people to comment.
把@追D放在上面 然後大家u
Every once in a while I hop and stir the pot to get a good debate going.
每隔一我就挑芤幌  好大家激烈
Was Mr. Zuckerberg
Zuckerberg先生
cheating on his final exam?
曾期末考作弊
I'd rather not answer that question.
我不回答的
And why not?
什麽
'Cause I'm not suing him for cheating on his final exam.
因我不是起V他期末考作弊
That's not what freinds do.
朋友是不@麽做的
Well, you just told us he was cheating.
你就在f他作弊
You told your lawyers I was torturing animals?
你告V律我虐待游锪
No, he didn't tell us about it at all.
]有  他]有f
Our litigators are capable of finding a Crimson article.
我律完全有能力找到篇校笪恼
In fact, when we raised the subject what maybe defended you.
我提到的r候可能|怒你
993. We are so close.
993了  快成功了
Oh, yeah, that reminds me....
我想起砹
we're gonna need more money, Eduardo.
我需要X  Eduardo
Yeah, I aggree. More servers, more apps.
我知道  需要更多的服掌骱用程序
I'm interviewing two interns to come to
我要招生去
Palo Alto and we are going to have to pay them something.
帕_W多  我得o他cX
Sorry, what?
不好意思  什麽
I've already found a house for rent on a street
我已在x斯坦福大W街^h的地方
two blocks from the Stanford Campus. It's perfect and it's got a pool.
找好了房子  特好  有游泳池
When did you decide to go to Califrnia for the summer?
你什麽r候决定暑假去加州的
You mean when did I actually decide?
你意思是我什麽r候真正决定
Somewhere in the middle of the Sean Parker variety hour?
是在Sean Parker表演秀中g
He was right. California is the place we gotta be.
他f的  我得去加州
What? You're Jed Clampett?
什麽   你是Jed Clampett[美演T]
You got the Beverly Hillbillies in Brazil?
你在巴西也能看"弗利山人"啊
Shows in Brazil. Jesus.
在巴西的表演秀  天啊
What is your problem with Sean?
你什麽Sean有成
He doesn't bring anything to the table,
他一c都拿不出手
doesn't have money, Dustin's a better programmer.
]X  Dustin都比他程
He's got connections to VCs.
他能M投Y公司
To VCs?
投Y公司?
If we need advertisers, I have connections to VCs.
如果我需要V告商  我也能M投Y公司
He's a real player.
他是行家
And as someone who's just really embarrased the company in a bad way.
b于某人o公司造成了O牡挠绊
It was the
是WinkleVosses
WinkleVosses, Mark.
p胞胎值  Mark
Hang on.
等下
Here we refresh.
刷新下
150,004.
150,004人了
150,000 members, Eduardo.
150,000T了  Eduardo
- Congratulations. - Congratulations.
-太好了  -太好了
You don't think it was strange
你不X得他被私家商礁踪的事
that he was followed by private detectives?
特e异
Who came up with nothing?
l能]c故事
Enough to get him out of the company,
{@就o他s出公司了
the drugs the girls?
有吸毒和E交呢
We don't know if any of that is true.
我都不知道@些是不是真的
We can read about it.
我能看出戆
I can read about you torturing birds,
我能看出砟闩按小呢
since we're reading about something...
因我看到...
Eat no fish! Eat no fish?
不吃~的啊  他不吃~的
The marlins and the trout.
~和q~
What's he talking about?
他f什麽呢
I'm interviewing interns at 10 tommorow
我明晚十c在CS室面生
night in the CS lab. Get on board with these men, you know.
和他好好相吧
I don't really know what else to say.
e的我就不f什麽了
Eduardo!
Eduardo
What's going on?
@是在
They have 10 minutes to
他有十分rg@取
get root access to a python web server,
脚本服掌鞯墓芾T嘞
expose its SSL encryption, and then intercept all traffic over its secure port.
破解密a  然後r截所有安全端口的流量
They are hacking.
他是黑客
Yes. All behind a PIX Firewall Emulator,
只是在模M器上M行
but here is the beauty.
但@才是好玩的地方
You know I didn't understand anything you just said, right?
你知道你才f的我都不懂吧
I do know that.
我知道
So what's the beauty?
好玩在哪
Every 10th line of code written they have to take a shot,
每好十行代a  他得喝一杯
and hacking supposed to be stealth, so anytime the
黑客要行o  所以如果
server detects an intrusion, the candidate responsible has to take a shot.
被服掌r截  他也得喝一杯
I also have a program running that has
我有件能5台X
a pop-up window appear simultaneously on all 5 computers.
同r出窗口
The last candidate to hit the window has to take a shot.
P]窗口最慢的也要喝一杯
Plus every 3 minutes they all have to take a shot.
有每三分他都要喝一杯
Three minutes!
到c了
Can I ask what part of the
我想知道生什麽工作
interns' job will they need to be able to do drunk?
要求他@麽能喝
You're right. A more relavant test would
你f得  是看他能不能把B活
be seeing if they can keep a chicken alive for a week.
一Y拜的考更N切c
That was mean.
我太缺德了
Here.
o
What is this?
什麽
I opened a new acount and put 18000 dollars in it.
我新_了~  存了18000美元
Will that get you through the summer?
够你一夏天用的
Welcome to Facebook.
g迎加入Facebook
- 18000 dollars? - Yes.
-18000美元  -
- In addition to the 1000 dollars you already put up. - Yes.
-不算你已存的1000K  -
A total of 19,000 dollars now.
共有19000美元
Hang on. Just checking your math on that.
等下  我算算Σ
I got the same thing.
我算的跟你一
May I continue?
我能^m
After expressing missgivings about Mr.
在表_了他Zuckerburg先生
Zuckerburg taking the company and moving it to California
要在暑假把公司w移到加州的n]之後
for the summer, why did you
什麽你是要
put 18000 dollars in the account for his use?
在纛^上存18000美元o他
I figured we were partners.
我X得我是拍n
I wanted to be a team player.
我想成一T
I figured Mark, Dustin
我想在Mark和Dustin
and the new interns could
以及新淼生
work on the site while I was generating advertiser interest in New York.
做W站的同r  我在~s找V告投Y商
But mostly I figured,
我想怎麽著  三月
how much could possibly go wrong in 3 months?
糟能糟到什麽程度啊
- I didn't die. - I know.
-我]死  -我知道
- I made it. - You did.
-我成功了  -的_
OK. Ready?
好了  浜昧
Davo's like an egg.
DavoL的跟蛋似的
That was like a tooth.
更像w牙
He's better than that.
比那能好c
I'm ok.
我]事
- You're sure? - Nice.
-真的  -那就好
That's the doorbell.
T了
I didn't know we had a doorbell.
@有T呢啊
Andrew, get the door.
Andrew  去_T
No, he's wired in.
e  他正忙著呢
That's gonna cut into the security deposit.
得难航鹧Y扣X了
- Andrew. - I'm knocked down. - Good boy.
-Andrew  -忙著呢  -乖
- Sean?  - Mark.
-Sean  -Mark
Do you live here?
你在@住
We live right across the street, we saw the chimney...
我就在街γ孀  看到烟...
Is anbody hurt?
有人受
You look...
你看起...
We live across the street.
我就在γ孀
I'm Sharon.
我是Sharon
This is my...Sharon.
她是我的...  Sharon
She lives across the street.
她在街γ孀
I was helping her move out, we saw the chimney...
我退搬家呢  看到烟...
Yeah. We had a little accident by the pool.
]事  泳池出了c小}
You came to California.
你砑又萘
You made the right choice.
值闷亮
- There you go. - Sharon.
-接著  -Sharon
- I'm so sorry. - No problem.
-不好意思  -]事
- I didnt know you are gonna... - There you go.
-我不知道你要...  -接著
No, wait!
e  等下
This house and this team are great exactly what it should be.
@房子有整F就@
I'm Sean Parker.
我是Sean Parker
Oh, he's wired in.
他正忙著呢
That's what I'm talking about.
要的就是@B
Where's Eduardo?
Eduardo哪去了
He got an internship in New York.
他在~s
Eduardo didn't come out?
字幕
I was crashing there for a little bit while I am taking care of somethings.
我在那住段rg便照照她
But she's done for the summer so she's back at her parents palce.
但她就要_W了  所以就回父母那了
The homeless rock star at Palo Alto.
帕_W多的o家可wuL巨星
Alright.
]e
What's your plan for the summer?
@夏天的是什麽
Im sorry I was looking at the architecture.
抱歉  我在看建B
I asked what your plans were.
我在你的打算
Honour school till the end of the summer.
整暑假都在W校
- We are going to the washroom.  - OK.
-我去洗手g  -好
Your date looks so familiar to me.
我X的你的女伴很眼熟
She looks familiar to a lot of people.
很多人多X得她眼熟
What do you mean?
什麽意思
My statment is that Roy Raymond
我在fRoy Raymond
wants to buy his wife some lingerie.
想o他的妻子I纫
But he's to embarased to shop
但他不好意思在
for it in a department store,
百商店I
comes up with an idea for a high end place
他想到了一主意  身高管
that doesn't make you feel like a pervert.
就不像色狼了
He gets a 40.000 dolar bank,
他你y行J款四f美元
loan borrows another 40.00 thosand from his in-laws.
又墓婆那Y借了四f美元
Opens a store and calls it Victoria Secret.
_O了一家名"Victoria Secret"的商店
Makes half million dollars the first year.
@家商店每年盈利五十f美元
So the guy catalogued 3 more stores and after 5 years,
所以他又_立了三家分店  五年後
he sells the company
他以四百f的r格
to Leslie Wester Unlimited for 4 million dollars.
⒐司uo了Leslie Wester Unlimited
Happy ending right.
好Y局吧
Besides, 2 years later,
另外  赡赆
the company is worth 500 million dollars.
@家公司r值五百f美元
And Roy Raymond jumps off the Golden Gate Bridge.
Roy Raymond慕痖T大蚩v深跳下
The poor guy just want to buy back wife that he has.
他只想要回他的老婆
Was that a parable?
你是在暗指我
I date Victoria Secret models.
我和Victoria Secret的模特s
That's why she looks familiar to you.
所以你看她眼熟
Don't be impressed by all this. I read your Blog
e太@  我x^你的博客
Oh, you know that was for white pretty
你知道那是o白I女孩看的
You know why I started Napster?
你知道我什麽建Napster
The girl loved in high school
我喜g的高中女生
was with the co-captain of the varsity lacross team.
是校曲棍球L之一
And I wanted to take her from him.
我想乃手中把她^
So I decided to come up with the next big thing.
所以我要做一番大事I
I didnt know that.
我不明白
Napster wasn't a failure.
Napster不是失〉L
I changed the music industry for better and for allways.
至少我永久性地改了音樊bI
It may not have been good business.
@也S]有很好的商I前景
And it pissed a lot of people off.
惹怒了很多人
And isn't that what your Facemash was about?
@y道不是你的"撕破W站"的|
Their sacred of me pal.
他害怕我  夥
And their gonna be sacred of you.
他也害怕你
And the business wanna say, good idea kid.
商人f  小朋友  好c子
Grown-ups are gonna take it from here.
粝在@Yl芽
But not this time. This is our time.
但不是@r代  F在是我的r代
This time you goona hand over a business card
@r代你手持的胸卡著
that says Im CEO, bitch.
混蛋  我才是首席绦泄
That's what I want from you.
@是我δ愕钠谕
So were the hell is Eduardo?
Eduardo他去哪了
He's in New York.
他在~s
Sucking up to Ad Execs.
去好V告高管了
He's got a internship.
他是去了
The companies here, a billion dollar companies here.
@Y公司太多了  挡
- Do you ever read Facebook.  - Yes.
-你看Facebook  -是的
I know you do.
我就知道
Eduardo wants to be a business manager.
Eduardo想成I战理
And for all I know he'll be a good one,
我所知  他值煤艹錾
but he shoud'nt be in New York
但他不在~s
kissing Madison Avenues ass.
好迪d大道的人
This is a once in a generation holy shit idea.
@他就是@代人的^念
And the water under the Golden Gate is freezing cold.
金T大蛳曼I的水很冷
Look at my face
看著我的
and tell me I dont know what Im talking about.
ξ艺f"我不知道我f什麽了"
You ever think about that girl?
你想^那女孩
What girl?
哪女孩
The the girl from high school
那名{君越
who was with the Lacross thing.
的高中女生
No.
]有
Did any of your guys talk about that MS?
你是在MS
- All you got is till the end of the summer?  - Yeah.
-你整暑假都要做@  -是
Tell you what, just think with your feet,
我告V你  傻子都知道
When you get into honour school,
你跨M粝氲拇Wr
I'll put you on 2 continents.
我把你放在善大上
2 continents.
善大
You don't have a place to crash
你]地方跳
I think you shouls definitely come live with us.
我J你肯定和我住在一起
Let's line up some shots.
我一起ふC
Excuse me.
服T
You can take this away and bring back the 1922.
把@拿走  Щ匾痪哦二年
Absoloutely Mr.Parker.
]}  Parker先生
Tyler
Tyler
Thank you.
xx
Oh and this is my brother Cameron?
@不是Cameron兄弟
His Royal highness Prince Albert.
Albert王子殿下
Your highness this is Taylor and Cameron WinkleVoss.
@是Taylor和WinkleVoss
Of course brilliant race.
精彩^的比
- I've never seen a race that close.  - Yes, sure.
-我奈匆^如此激烈的比  -是的
My grandfather Jack Kelly was one of the premiere rowers.
我的祖父Jack Kelly艇首lT之一
I've been coming to HENLEY for 30 years.
我磉@已三十年了
And I've never seen a race that close.
我奈匆^如此激烈的比
Have you have you seen a race that close?
你看^@麽激烈的比
No, your highness.
]有  殿下
Mile and a half races
一英里半的比
are more commonly won by a boat length or two.
通常差距在一至伤掖的距x
Yes, that's absloutely right.
]e  是@拥
Brutally close.
@太激烈了
May I introduce my teamate...
允S我向您介B我的F友...
I'm sorry. You have to excuse us.
抱歉  我失陪一下
We flew all the way out here to do that?
我w^砭了做@事
Would'nt of missed it, brother.
不要e^了  兄弟
Hows the royalty?
和王室聊得如何
Ah, he just wanted to tell me a couple of times
他只是在不嘀匮}
how close the race was.
比多麽激烈
Just brutally, brutally excruciating.
激烈到忍了
Cam, the guys the prince of a country
Cam  和楠塔基特u一哟蟮
the size of Nantucket. Relax, fine.
小的王子  e在意
Boys.
小夥子
Mr.WinkleVoss.
WinkleVoss先生
That was a tough beat.
真是銎Dy的比
Im sorry dad you and Mom had to fly all this way
抱歉您和母H@麽hw^
to see this.
看到我了
No, son.
不  鹤
Don't apologise to me for loosing a race like that.
不要因了比而@酉蛭业狼
I'd never apologise to anyone
我]因了比
for loosing a race like that.
而@酉蛉魏稳说狼
Boys.
小夥子
Mister Kenright.
Kenright先生
Dad this Mister Kenright,
父H  @是Kenright先生
part of our host family this week
@周比的主k人之一
-Pleasuer to meet you.  - Pleasure to meet you.
-幸  -幸
I had a chat with my daughter.
我和女毫牡竭^
She told me that she and her freinds
她ξ艺f  她和她的朋友
allready talking about the race
已在通^X
which they've just seen via their computers.
我才看到的@霰荣了
A new website called Facebook,
一叫做Facebook的W站
Do you have this in America?
美有@W站
I'm gonna find your mother.
我去找你母H
Did I say something wrong?
我fe什麽了
Your daughter does'nt go to school in the States?
您女翰辉诿上W
No. No. Cambridge. Majoring in french literature.
不  她在虼W  主修法文W
Though I was'nt aware there was such a thing.
管我J是不重要
They have Facebook at Cambridge?
虼W有Facebook
And apparently Oxford and the London School of Economics
涨绎@然  牛津和敦政治W院
for the present.
目前也有了
Disaster.
真是灾y
Good race boys, live to fight another day.
表F不e  下次努力
Somebody watch my stuff.
有人在P注我的|西
Someone I want to see it  -stop it
我想看看@人  -住手吧
Stop, Cam.
Cam  e@
Knock it off.
e查了
I don't mind that we
我不介意我
lost to the Dutch by less then a secound.
以不到一秒的差距o荷m人
That was a good race.
我得很出色
And that was a fair race, that was good race.
@是龉平的比  很漂亮
what I mind and you should mind
我介意的是你想想
showing up on Monday for a race that was run on Sunday
周日有比  他周一才F身
We tried talking to him ourselves,
我^找他
we tried writing a letter,
^信o他
we'd tried the add board,
登^V告
and we tried talking to the president of the university.
找^校L
Now I am asking you for the last time.
F在我最後一次拜托你
Let's take the considerable resources at our disposal.
一起奈的角度想想k法吧
And sew him in Federal court.
在他上邦法庭前挽救他
Come on.
拜托
I need a real drink.
我要去喝c|西
Screw it.
去他的
Let's gut the friggin nerd.
我Я四窃死的呆子
Check it out, I saw him today.
查下  我昨天看到他了
Manningham, Mitchel Manningham.
Manningham  Mitchel Manningham
Are you guys the Wallhacks or Aimbots?
你是在玩使命召
We don't know were just shooting at each other.
不知道  我只是在互相射
Use the kamikaze.
用神LT
Like we know what that is.
好像我掌握要I了
I saw him getting into his Turbo Carrera,
我看到他走Mu增旱谋r捷
and he saw me too.
他也看到我了
I know he did.
他一定看到了
Don't. Don't sweety. I want to go on-line.
不要@  甜心  我要上W
Does any of you get banging?
有人打A了
You can't hear anything your writing code.
你代a的r候不到任何音
Hey, somebody's at the door.
有人敲T
It's not...
@不是...
I'm gonnna call you back.
我回^打o你
What's up?
怎麽了
Mark was supposed to pick me up
Mark于
at the airport an hour ago,
一小r前在C鼋游
I've been calling his cell.
我o他去^了
He was on a 36 hour coding tear,
他Bm工作了三十六小r
so he took a nap for a few hours.
所以他需要休息仔r
What happened here?
l生什麽了
Not happened, happening.
不是l生什麽了  是正在l生
Next big thing.
又一件大事
Eduardo.
Eduardo
- Hey man.  - Back to work.
-你好  -帜愕氖氯
Sorry about it, its the more wasted I get.
抱歉  我做@真是浪M
I meant the more...
我的意思是更...
We understand.
我懂了
How old are they, Sean?
她多大了  Sean
It's not polite to ask.
@麽不Y貌
Sean, how old are they?
Sean  她多大了
You think you know me, right?
你J你t解我吧
I've read enough.
我看^够了
You know how much I've read about you?
你知道我δ阌卸嗖t解
-Eduardo.  -Hey, man.
-Eduardo  -夥
I waited an hour for you from the airport.
我在C龅攘四阋小r
What time is it?
F在c了
Midnight, it was 3am in New York where I just came from.
午夜  ~srgR晨三c
You got to see some of the new stuff we got.
JR一下我的新成T
Dustin show him the wall.
Dustin  他看看""
I'm just calling it the wall.
我把它叫做""
Forget about the wall,
e管""了
tell him about the meeting I got setup.
告V他我要出席的h
You know Peter Thiel?
你JRPeter Thiel
Nope
不JR
No reason you should.
]理由不知道
He runs funded a 2 billion dollar hedge fund
他I著|美元的_基金
called Clarium Capital.
叫做Clarium基金的
Why's he setting up meetings for you?
他什麽要你
Thiel may want to make an angel investment.
Thiel也S是想做天使投Y[I初期的LU投Y]
I don't care if hes an actual angel.
我不管他是不是只天使
Why is he setting up business meetings?
什麽他要召_上午h
You've had a long flight.
你v了一鲩L途w行
No. I had a long wait at Tarmac at JFK,
不  我在肯尼迪Cr青路上等了很久
then a long wait at the
又在f金山HC龅
passenger loading and unloading zone at SFO,
旅客托\行李除等了很久
and in between there was a long flight.
@之g是一次L途w行
I'm the business end of this company.
我公司的I彰β
And he is a house guest living here rent free
而他是在@Y吃白的
with a very generous grant
由EduardocSeverin基金
from the Eduardo Severin Foundation.
慷慨地授c
I heard about your big ticket
我f你在C票的ぱY
add buys "Jerry's Tuxedos"
加M了JerryIY服的花M
Hey man.
夥
The Harvard Bartending Course course.
有哈佛{酒n程
Your just one small step away
你差c就I了
from bagging Snookies Cookies.
斯努克乾
Can I talk to you alone for a minute?
我能和你为一
Sure.
]}
Bong hit.
抽大麻
I'm so high.
我太^a了
Hows it going, Hows the internship, Hows Christy?
怎  如何  Christy怎
Hows the internship?
如何
Mark, jesus, I quit the internship.
Mark  的  我退出了
We talked abou this on the phone,
@我在Yf^了
I quit on my first day.
我第一天就不至
I do rememebr you saying that.
我是得你f^
Sounds real.
是的
Christy's crazy.
Christy了
Is that fun?
很有趣
No.
不
Psychotic, she's insanely jealous, she's irrational.
她是精神病患者  嫉妒狂  失去理性
And I'm frightened of her.
我怕她了
Still it's nice you have a girlfreind.
至少你有女友
I do not want that guy.
我不喜g那砘
Representing himself as part of this company.
自以是@家公司的一T
You got move out here, Eduardo
Eduardo  你出去了
this is where it all happening.
Fl生在@Y
Did you hear what I just said?
你到我f的了
The connections is the energy.
M就是力量
Mark, Mark, come on
Mark  拜托
I'm afraid if you don't come out here
恐怕如果你不回
your going to be left behind.
你就被落下了
I want I want I mean you
我想  我的意思是
What did you just say?
你f什麽
It's growing faster then any of us imagined it be.
它比我想像得成L得更迅速
It's moving fast and Sean thinks that we should...
l展太快了  SeanJ我...
Sean's not part of this company.
Sean不儆谶@家公司
We have over 300 thousand memebers
我在一百六十所W校
were in 160 schools.
碛谐^三十f的用
I'm aware.
我知道
Including 5 in Europe.
包括W洲的五所
I'm aware of that, Mark.
@我知道  Mark
Mark, I'm the CFO.
Mark  我是湛O
We need more programmers and we need more money,
我需要更多的目和更多的X
and he setup the Thiel meeting.
他恿伺cThiel的面
Hes setup meetings all over town.
他j了整城市
Setup other meetings?
恿似渌h?
Yes.
是的
Without me knowing anything about it.
在我全然不知的情况下
Your were in New York.
你那r在~s
Im in New York riding subways 14 hours a day.
我在~s一天十四小r坐地F
Try explaining that to me.
你解看看
Yeah. And hows it going so far?
是的  M展如何
What did you mean get left behind.
你f被落下是什麽意思
Can I help you?
您想k理什麽I
I'd like to freeze this bank account,
我想鼋Y@~
and cancel all existing checks and lines of credit.
取消所有的F已存在的支票和透支渠道
May I see some ID please?
我能看您的身份C
Yeah, sure.
]}
Sean, he'll be right with you.
Sean  他R上就能你了
You know this where they filmed The Towering Inferno.
他就是在@Y拍z了《火摩天恰
Hey guys, come on back.
你M戆
Did she offer you some water
她你接水了
Oh yeah, were cool.
是的  很酷
You must be Mark.
你就是Mark吧
We took a look at everything and congratulations.
我大致看了一下  恭喜
We're gonna start you off with a
我先你注入
500 thousand dollar investment.
五十f美元的淤Y金
Maurice is going to talk to you about
Maurice跟你
some corporate restructurng.
企I重M的事
Well file as a corporation in Delaware.
特拉A洲的n案
We've come up with a
我找到一
sound structure that will allow us to invest.
不e的投YY
Now let me ask you something.
F在我想你件事
Who's Eduardo Severin?
l是Eduardo Severin
Jesus.
天啊
When did you get back?
你什麽r候回淼
You scared me, I need you to knock.
你到我了  敲T
I got back this afternoon.
今天下午
and when are you gonna call me?
你打算什麽r候o我打
Jesus, it was kind of a bad trip.
天啊  旅途很糟糕
And I was tired.
我十分疲v
or answer 1 of my 47 texts,
或是回答我四十七l短信的其中一l
did you know I sent 47 texts.
你知道  我l了四十七l
I did.
收到了
And I thought that was incredibly normal behaviour.
涨椅艺J@是^φ常的行
Are you mocking me?
你是在愚弄我
I bought you a present.
我o你ЯY物
Why does your status say single on your Facebook page?
什麽你在Facebook的B是紊
Why does your relationship
什麽你在Facebook的
status say single on your Facebook page?
情感B的是紊
I was single when I set up the page.
我建立那的r候是紊
And you never bothered to change it?
那就不更改
What?
什麽
I dont know.
我不
Do I look stupid to you?
你X得我蠢
No, calm down.
]有  冷o
Your asking me to believe that the CFO of Facebook
你我相信你是Facebook的首席展
does'nt know how to change
而却不更改
his relationship status on Facebook?
在Facebook上的B
A little embarassing.
我感到羞愧
You should take it as a sign of trust
你孕
that I would tell you that.
我δ阏f的
Go to hell.
去死吧
Take it easy.
放
You did'nt change it
你]改是因
so you could SCREW those little Silicon Valley sluts.
@幽憧梢哉幸一些矽谷的小D
That's not even remotely true.
@太xV了
And I can promise you that
涨椅铱梢韵蚰惚ＷC
the Silicon Valley sluts don't care about
矽谷的小D不在意
anybodys relationship status on Facebook.
任何人的Facebook上的B
Please open your present.
打_你的Y物
Your phone does work.
你的手C牧
It's Mark.
是Mark
Uh, open you present.
打_你的Y物
It's a scarf.
是l巾
Have you ever seen me wear a scarf?
你^我巾
This'll be your first.
那就_始О
Yeah.
是我
You froze our accounts?
你鼋Y了~
I did.
是的
I had to get you attention Mark.
我要引起你的注意  Mark
Do you realise that you jeapordised the entire company?
你意R到你@在害@公司
Do you realise that your actions
你意R到你的e
could have permanetly destroyed
或S已永久性地缌
everything I've been working on?
我所作的一切
We've have been working on.
我的所作的一切
Without money the site cant function.
Y金嗔司W站就o法\行
OK, let me tell you the
好吧  我砀嬖V你
difference between Facebook and everone else.
Facebook和其他W站的^e
We dont crash ever.
我的W站牟槐
If the servers are down for even a day,
如果服罩嗔四呐乱惶
our reputation is irreversibly destroyed.
我的u就Я
Look,
著
They have their friends and crews there.
那上面有他的朋友和T工
Even a few people leaving would reverberate, through.
即使只有很少的人x_了也有影
The whole user database.
整用
The users are interconnected, thats the whole point.
用糁g的互是PI
College kids are line cause their freinds are online.
W生在Q是因他的朋友在Q
And if one domino goes,
如果一K多米Z骨牌倒了
the other domino goes dont you get that.
後面的接B倒下去
Don't you get that?
你y道不知道
I am not going back to the Carribean night of 85.
我不想再回去住八十五一晚的旅店了
Holy shit.
天⒌
What's wrong with you?
你怎麽了
Did you like being nobody?
你想默默o
Did you like being a joke?
你想回大家眼Y的笑柄
Do you want to go back to that?
你想回原砟
Hang on. Hang on.
等等  e挂
That was the act of a child not a businessman
只有小孩才@麽做  根本不像商人
certainly not the act of a freind
更不像是朋友
You know how embarssed I was to cash a check today.
你不知道我今天去Q支票r有多y堪
I am not going back to that life.
我^不要再^@拥娜兆
Maybe you were frustrated.
可能你沮柿
Maybe you were angry.
可能你生饬
I was.
我是
But I am willing to let by gones
但是我意@件事^去
be bygones because Eduardo I've got some good news.
因  Eduardo  我有好消息
I'm sorry I was angry and maybe it was childish.
抱歉我生饬  可能@很幼稚
But I had to get your attention.
但是我必要引起你的注意
Eduardo I said I've got some good news.
Eduardo  我f我有好消息了
What is it?
什麽好消息
Peter Thiel has made an
Peter Thielo了我
angel investment of half a million dollars.
一P五十f美元的天使投Y
What?
什麽
Half a million dollars.
五十f美元
And he's setting us up in an office.
他o我提供了一gk公室
They want to re-incorporate the company.
他想要把公司重新合
They want to meet you they need your signature on some documents,
他想你  要你一些文件
you got get your ass on the first flight back to San Francisco,
你必o我坐上最近的一班wC回San Francisco
I need my CFO.
我需要我的CFO
I'm on my way.
我F在
Eduardo.
Eduardo
We did it.
我成功了
You're going back there already.
你又要回去那了
Yes.
是的
And also I'm breaking up with you.
我要跟你分手
4 documents.
一共四份文件
The first 2 are common stock purchase agreements allowing you to buy
前煞菔瞧胀ü善辟Ifh
stock in the newly re-incorporated Facebook
它能你I重新合蔗Facebook的新股
instead of the old shares which are now worthless.
而不是已不值X的原砉司的f股
The third is an exchange agreement,
第三份是一份交Qfh
allowing you to exchange old shares for new shares.
允S你用f股Q新股
And finally the voter holding agreement.
最後一份是股|控股fh
How many shares of stock will I own
有多少股票是我的
1,328,334
一百三十二f八千三百三十四
That represents 34.4% ownership share.
占了所有喾蓊~Y的百分之三十四c四
Why the increase from the original 30%.
至于什麽淖畛醯陌俜种三十q到F在
Because you may dilute to award shares to new investors.
因你需要稀股票把股喾稚⒔o新股|
I love working with business majors, don't you?
我就喜g和懂行人打交道
You should know that Mark has already
要知道Mark已把他的份~
taken his 60 down to 51.
陌俜种六十降到百分之五十一了
Well, Mark doesn't care about the money
Mark不在乎X的}
and he needs to be protected.
他需要被保o起
Dustin Markowitz down to 6.81%.
Dustin Markowitz的占百分之六c八一
Sean Parker 6.47%.
Sean Parker占百分之六c四七
I can live with that.
@游铱梢越邮
And Peter Thiel 7%.
Peter Thiel占百分之七
Would you like to use my pen?
需要用我的P
Eduardo.
Eduardo
Can you please repeat the question?
能麻┠阍倌钜槐}
No, it was an outrageously leading question
不能  @}第一次的r候
the first time
才有引效果
and now you want hear it twice.
F在你想第二次
Yes, will you read it back please?
是的  麻┠阍一遍}
Go ahead.
^m
Counsel and were you aware that when you were signing
律  你字的r候你知道的
these documents that you were signing your own death certificate.
是你自己的死亡C明
No.
不知道
It was insanely stupid of
我值淖钌档囊患事
me not to have lawyers look at all this stuff.
就是]我自己的律臀铱纯茨切┪募
In all honesty I thought they were my lawyers.
老f  我以他就是我的律
I was your only freind.
我曾是你唯一的朋友
You had one freind.
你曾唯一的朋友
My father won't even look at me.
我的父H甚至都不再看我一眼了
OK. Eduardo, did Mr Zuckerberg say
好了  Eduardo  Mr Zuckerberg在你名之後
anything to you after you had signed the papers?
跟你f了什麽
There was a lot of hand shaking a lot of congratulations.
大家都砀我握手  祝R我
He already told me that he wouldn't
他早就跟我f了
be coming back to school for at least a semester.
至少一W期之人是不回W校上n的
So we were saying good bye for a while.
所以我之前就已互相道e^了
- And before I left he said. - You gotta come back
-但在我x_之前他f  -你得回
Some time around the end of November, early December,
Peter湓谑一月底十二月初
Peter wants to throw as an amazing party when we hit a million members.
我碛幸话偃fT的r候k一派
Its gonna be out of control you gotta come back for it.
你不在的一切都y套的
A million members.
一百fT
Remember the algorithm
得那公式
on the window at Kirkland.
我在Kirkland窗羯系哪
Yeah, I'll be here.
我淼
You sure about this
你_定要@麽
You're 20 minutes late.
你已t了二十分了
You're gonna walk in there and say you
你要走M那Y
overslept and you didn't have time to get dressed.
告V他你睡^^了  聿患Q衣服
They're gonna pitch you case equities.
他只根你的公司决定要不要投Y你
They're gonna pitch you. They're gonna beg you to take their money.
他投Y你的  他求著要o你X
You're gonna nod, you're gonna nod and then you're
你只要c^再c^
gonna say which one of you is Roth?
然後  你l是Roth
No, not Roth. Manningham.
不  不叫Roth  叫Manningham
Which one of you is Mitchel Manningham?
l叫Mitchel Manningham
And he'll say I am
然後他就f我是
and you say Sean Parker says fuck you.
你就告V他Sean Parkerf操你
Walk out.
然後走人
Ok.
好
In late November I got the e-mail from Mark
十一月底我收到一封Markl淼泥]件
telling me to come out to the late million member party.
我去⒓c祝百fT的派
What else did the e-mail say?
]件Yf了什麽
It said that we had to have a business meeting
f  我需要_一商Ih
that Mark and Sean had
就是那次hMark和Sean
played some kind of revenge stunt on case equity.
在公司股嗌贤媪统鹗侄
And Manningham was so impressed that he
@件事oManningham留下了O深的印象
was now making an investment offer that was hard to turn down.
以至于他_出了更y以拒^的投Y
So I went to California and I went straight to the new offices.
所以我到了California直接去了新的k公室
I did'nt know whether to
我不知道穿的像是去派Φ
dress for the party or the business meeting.
是穿的像是去_的
So I kind of dressed for both.
所以我穿了煞N龊隙歼m合的
But it didn't matter.
但@都不重要了
Why not?
什麽
Because I wasn't called out there for either one.
因我被叫去既不是要_也不是要派
What were you called out there for?
那是因什麽
An ambush.
一次伏
Mr Severin, right over here.
Mr Severin  @
At first I thought he was joking
_始我以他在_玩笑
giving me more contrcts to sign.
要o我更多的合s署
But then I started reading
直到我J真看了才知道
Wait. What is this?
等等  @是什麽
Well, as you know we had some new investors that...
你也知道的  我有些新的投Y者
What is this?
@是什麽
Severin.
Severin
Mark.
Mark
- He's wired in. - Sorry.
-他在工作  -抱歉
- He's wired in. - Is he?
-他在工作  -是
Yes.
是的
How about now are you still wired in?
那你F在在工作
Security.
叫保安
You issued 24 million new shares of stock.
你新l了汕四百f的股票
You were told that if new investors came along
我告V^你的如果有新的投Y者
How much were your shares diluted, how much were his
你的股票稀了多少  有他的呢
What were Mr Zuckerberg's ownership shares dilutes down to?
Mr Zuckerberg的股份被稀到了多少
It wasn't.
]
What were Mr Moscovtz's shares shares dilutes down to?
Mr Moscovtz的股份呢
What were Sean Parker's shares shares dilutes down to?
Sean Parker的股份呢
It wasn't.
]
What were Peter Thiel's shares shares dilutes down to?
Peter Thiel的股份呢
And what were your ownership shares diluted down to?
那你的股份呢
.03 percent.
百分之零c零三
You signed the papers.
你了合同的
You set me up.
你算我
You're gonna blame me because you were the business head
你怪我是因即使你是公司商I的^
of the company and you made a bad business deal with your own company.
却是跟自己公司做了rXIu
It's gonna be like im not a part of Facebook.
@的好像我不是Facebook的一份子
Won't be like your not a part of Facebook,
不是好像你不是Facebook的一份子
you're not a part of Facebook.
而是你根本就不是Facebook的一份子
My name's on the masthead.
l行人谘Y有我的名字
You may want to check again.
你再去看看清楚
Is because I froze the account?
是因我鼋Y了~
You think we were gonna let you parade around in
你X得我你穿著你可笑的西b
your ridiculous suit and pretending you were running this company.
在@Yz  假b你在I@家公司
Sorry my Prada's at the cleaners,
抱歉我的Prada拿去洗了
along with my hoodie and fuck-you flip flops.
和我的B帽衫有他的人字拖一起
You pretentious douche bag.
你@自以是的混蛋
Securty's here and you'll be leaving now.
保安砹  你走了
I'm not signing those papers.
我是不那些死的文件的
We will get your signature.
我你字的
Tell me this isn't about me getting into the Phoenix.
告V我@不是因我M了Phoenix
You..You did it. I knew you did it,
是你值  我就知道是你
you planted that story about the chicken.
是你安排的那的故事
I didn't plant that story about the chicken.
那的事情不是我安排的
What's he talking about?
他在f什麽
You had me accused of animal cruelty.
你害我因虐待游锉黄鹪V
Seriously, what the hells the chicken?
f真的  你他的在v什麽
And I bet what you hated most was that
我打你最恨的事
they identified me as a co-founder of Facebook
他把我成是Facebook的k人之一
which I am.
而我_是
You better lawyer up asshole.
你最好律  混蛋
Cause I'm not coming back for 30%,
因我不只硪回我的百分之三十
I'm coming back for everything.
我回Z走一切的
- Get him out of here. - It's ok. I'm going.
-把他С鋈  -我自己走
Hang on.
等等
I almost forgot.
我差c忘了
Here's your 19 thousand dollars.
@是你的一f九千KX  但我把它
I wouldn't cash it
到你鼋Y的那~羯狭
though I drew it on the account you froze.
我冬F不出
I like sitting next to you Sean.
我喜g坐在你的旁  Sean
It makes me look so tough.
因那我看起砗芮看
That's it. That's our show for tonight people.
好了  我今晚的表演Y束了
I want to see everybody here geared
我希望你每人都浜
up for a party were going to walk into that club
走去那俱凡⒓优
like its Macy's parade,
就像是去⒓Macy's parade
Mackie, put it up on the screen, we've gotta almost be there.
Mackie  用大屏幕放  R上就一百f了
You alright.
你]事吧
You were kind of rough with him.
你λ有c^分了
That's life in the NFL.
@就是NFL的生活
You know you didn't have to be that rough on him.
你知道你]必要他那麽狠的
Listen. I'm putting together a party.
著  我在弄派α
Sean.
Sean
You didn't have to be that rough on him.
你]必要λ那麽狠的
He almost killed it.
他差cЯ诉@一切
I'll send flowers.
我送花去道歉的
Speaking of flowers
f到花
I'm putting together a party after the party
我湓谶@派Y束後再弄一派
at Cappa the Sigma.
在sigma的Cappa
Ashley's sister.
Ashley的姐姐
- Ashley. - Intern.
-Ashley -那生
Yep. I know who she is.
我知道她是l
Are you guys...
你是不是
Ashley and me? No.
我跟Ashley  ]有
I won't go to the party.
我不想去
Why?
什麽
Excuse me, Mark.
不好意思打_了  Mark
We were just talking about you.
我f到你
Just you're doing a really good job.
你工作做得很棒
Thanks. I appreciate that.
xx  我很高d
These came in for you.
@些是你的
Put it on my desk.
放我桌上
What's the package?
包裹Y的是什麽
Nothing.
]什麽
Mackie.
Mackie
Yes, sir.
是  先生
Refresh.
更新
You gotta hugger.
我得肀б幌
I know.
我就知道
1 million
一百f
Who's got champagne?
lЯ讼
I've got champagne.
我Я
The next transformative, development of picture sharing application,
下一步的D就是可以你看到你
a place where you view pictures that coincide with your social life.
社交生活照片的D片共享用程序的l展
It is the true, the elevation of your life
是你生活的真照
- CD? - Good enough for me.
-放歌  -我X得不e
You don't just go to a party anymore.
你不再HH是去一派
You go to a party with a
你去的是一е荡a相C功能的派
digital camera and your freinds re-live the party online.
你的朋友可以在W上再次w@雠
and tagging the idea
能把他的想法留在下面
Would it be easier without the bra?
不穿胸罩不更方便一c
Guys, we'll find it out.
我R上就知道了
Shut the music down. Everybody go.
把音逢P掉  所有人起
I spend hours watching what people do when they login on
我花了很多rg^察人登以後质谗
Have they check their freinds status update?
他有]有去查看朋友的B更新
Wait. That's wired. Why did the music stop?
等等  奇怪  音吩貅嵬Ａ
They can see when their freinds change their profile
每他的朋友改Y料餍抡掌的r候
change their photos and mostly
他都可以看到  有
Seriously, what happen to the music?
f真的  那音吩貅嵬Ａ
We lived on farms.
我曾生活在r
And now we live in cities
F在我生活在城市
and now were going to live on the interent.
占⑸活在WjY
Sean, stop.
Sean  ef了
I think something's going on downstairs.
我X得下面好像出事了
Attention, please. Party is over.
你都ey  派Y束了
It's the cops.
l子砹
Good to see you, officer.
很高d到你  警官
What can I do for you?
有什麽能湍愕
What's going on?
@Y怎麽回事
Was the music to loud? We were having a celebration.
是不是音诽大了  我在_c祝
Miss, I need you to button your blouse.
小姐  麻┠愦┖靡路
I can tell them to turn the music down.
我可以叫他把音逢P小
That's not mine.
那不是我的
Ok, we're going to need identification.
好了  我需要你的身份C
Keep your hands where we can see them.
把手放到我看得的地方
Oh my god.
我的天
You got anything else in your pockets I should know about
你口袋Y有什麽|西我知道的
No. No, sir.
]  ]了  警官
Don't be stupid now. I don't. I don't.
e稚凳  我]有  真的]有
What's this?
@是什麽
That's an inhaler pump.
@是吸入器泵
- And this. - It's an inhaler.
-那@呢  -@是吸入器
How old are you?
你都q了
21.
二十一
I'm 21.
我二十一
Lying makes it worse.
坦白
I'm sorry I shouldn't have lied.
Σ黄鹞也辉撒e的
Listen, something has happened.
著  出了c麻
It's alright. We're gonna be alright.
]事的  我R上就]事的
I've posted a bond.
我已付了保金
I wasn't doing anything, I mean I got allergies.
我δ切┻^敏所以我真的什麽都]
Interns.
那生
It was just a party.
那只是派
This is gonna be news. Sean, Its gonna be online in a second.
它被蟮赖  Sean  R上就出F在Wj上
I know.
我知道
You know with an intern.
你只知道一生
It's cool. I have it under control.
]事的  一切都在我掌握之中
I will get it under control.
我硖理
I will call someone and see what our next move is,
我去打  看看下一步怎麽k
but this is gonna be news now.
但@肯定被蟮赖
You don't think Eduardo was involved, do you?
你X得@事跟Eduardo有P
- You think - No.
-你不@麽X得  -不P他事
Or Mannie one of them..Somebody
或者Mannie他中的l  某人
Somebody sent the cocaine because it got in there
某人把可卡因放到那Y去了
You believe me. This gotta be find.
你相信我的  找到是l的
Right?
是
Go home, Sean.
回家吧  Sean
Mark.
Mark
We're done for the day.
今天的工作已Y束了
Yeah I was just---
我知道  我只是
What happened to Sean?
Sean怎麽了
He still owns 7% of the company.
他仍然碛泄司百分之七的股份
All you had all day was that salad, you want get something to eat.
你一整天就吃了c沙拉  想吃ce的
I can't.
我有事
I'm not a bad guy.
我不是娜
I know that.
我知道
In emotional testimony
在感情C~中
I assume 85% of it is exaggeration.
我J其中百分之八十五是F
And the other 15.
那剩下的百分之十五呢
Perjury.
^C
Creation mess me to devil.
造把我成魔鬼
What happens now?
@事F在是怎麽恿
Sean and the others are having a steak on university avenue.
Sean跟他去大W大道吃牛排了
Then they'll come back to the
等他吃完回到k公室
office and work on a settlement deal without you.
就背著你著手和解
- They're gonna settle...- Oh, yeah.
-他要和解  -]e
And your gonna have to pay a little extra.
而且你要付~外的封口M
Why?
什麽
So that these guys sign a non-disclosure aggrement,
@铀才保密fh
They say one unflatering word about you in public
@尤绻他在公\龊现v你的脑
and you own their wife and kids.
你就能得到他的一切了
I invented Facebook.
我k了Facebook
I'm talking about a jury.
我指的是陪F的}
I specialise in voire-dire jury selection.
我擅L于分析陪F的x
What a jury sees when they look at a defendant.
被告出Fr陪F的人都注意些什麽
Clothes, hair, speaking style, likability.
衣服  ^  f方式  可不可
Likability?
可不可
I've been licenced to pratice law for all of 20 months,
我了拿C已二十月了
and I could get a jury to believe
我可以陪F相信
you planted the story about Eduardo and the chicken.
是你O了的故事陷害了Eduardo
Watch what else.
不止@些
Why weren't you at Sean's sorority party that night?
什麽那晚你]去Sean的x派
You think I'm the one who called the police.
你X得是我把警察叫^去的
It does'nt matter.
@不是重c
I asked the question and now everybody is thinking about it.
我  他自己想出答案
You've lost your jury in the first 10 minutes.
才_始十分你就失去了陪F的支持
I was drunk and angry and stupid
我那r喝醉了  又怒又X子不清醒
And bloging.
了博客.
Pay them.
o他X
In the scheme of things just beat them ticket.
@N事情  只要o他X就行了
That's what Sean will tell you tomorrow
Sean明天肯定@麽跟你f的
You think anybody would mind
你X得有人介意我
if I stayed and used the computer for a minute?
留在@^m用弘X
I can't imagine it will be a problem.
然不有人介意
Thanks.
x了
I appreciate your help today.
xx你的兔
You're not an asshole, Mark.
你不是混蛋  Mark
You're just trying so hard to be.
你只是努力成一混蛋